<?xml version="1.0" ?>

<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Brian Dunnington</title>
        <link>http://briandunnington.com</link>
        <description>RSS feed for website</description>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>Copyright 2015 - Brian Dunnington</copyright>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 07:25:24 GMT</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 07:25:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>

        <item>
            <title>Goodbye Scenic Avenue</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/goodbye_1805</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/1805Scenic2.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>After over 10 years in this house, we are moving on (though just a few miles down the road).</p>

<p>When we bought the place, it was just a house on a dirt lot with weeds taller than my head. We spent countless hours both inside and out to make it a truly great place to live. Loads of great memories here and I will definitely miss it.</p>

<p><figure><img src="/img/1805/house1.jpg" class="largeimg" /></figure></p>

<p><figure><img src="/img/1805/house2.jpg" class="largeimg" /></figure></p>

<p><figure><img src="/img/1805/house3.jpg" class="largeimg" /></figure></p>

<p><figure><img src="/img/1805/house4.jpg" class="largeimg" /></figure></p>

<p><figure><img src="/img/1805/house5.jpg" class="largeimg" /></figure></p>

<p><figure><img src="/img/1805/house6.jpg" class="largeimg" /></figure></p>

<p><figure><img src="/img/1805/house7.jpg" class="largeimg" /></figure></p>

<p><figure><img src="/img/1805/house8.jpg" class="largeimg" /></figure></p>

<p><figure><img src="/img/1805/house9.jpg" class="largeimg" /></figure></p>

<p><figure><img src="/img/1805/house10.jpg" class="largeimg" /></figure></p>

<p>Although we spent a ton of time working on the place, we also got to spend a lot of time enjoying it as well. Even as we were selling the house, I enjoyed just going over there and sitting on the deck and watching the trees sway in the breeze.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/1805/backyard.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>I will miss sitting out here<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/1805/last_load.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>The very last load of stuff before we drove away forever<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>Thanks Scenic - you were a great house!</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/goodbye_1805</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/1805Scenic2_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Soup Box Derby 2018</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/soup_box_derby_2018</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/soupboxderby_seuss.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>We raced the <a href="/soup_box_derby_2010">kayak-strapped-to-two-bikes</a> for the <a href="/soup_box_derby_2014">a couple of years</a>, and then made some modifications and <a href="/soup_box_derby_2015">raced it again in 2015</a>. After taking a few years off, we were back at it this year with a brand new racer.</p>

<p>We teamed up with Robin and Tim (the mayor - fancy!) to build a Seussmobile full of floo-flounders and jing-janglers.</p>

<p>We used lots of feather boas and PVC and bits of an old drum kit. The local newspaper even did a story about us.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/soupboxderby/trees.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Truffula trees<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/soupboxderby/drums.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>We had drums and cymbals and horns to make sure we were the loudest racer on the course<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/soupboxderby/garage.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Almost finished<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/soupboxderby/newspaper.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>We're famous<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>Come race day, we donned our costumes and unveiled the racer. We werent the fastest racer, but were most definitely the crowd favorite. All in all, it was a super fun racer to build and to race.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/soupboxderby/crew.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>The whole Seussian crew: Cat in the Hat, Sam I Am, and Thing 1 and Thing 2<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/soupboxderby/racing.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Seussmobile in action<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2018 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/soup_box_derby_2018</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/soupboxderby_seuss_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>RIP Tom</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/tom_rowland</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_stevenspassvalley.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>I will be sure to take a run for you my friend</p>

<p><img src="/img/other/skibus2012.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/tom_rowland</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_stevenspassvalley_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Summer Adventure - Sampler Platter</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/summer_adventure_sampler</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/mailboxpeak.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>After a couple of years of successful Summer Adventures, we had another dud last year. Chris and I decided that this year we would focus more on the 'fun' part than the 'adventure' part so we decided to just do a bunch of fun day trips all over the state.</p>

<p>(I once again failed to take very many pictures, but here are a few to give you an idea.)</p>

<h4>Day 1: Mountain Bike @ Devils Gulch</h4>

<p>Chris and I actually tried to ride here back in 2013 but it was closed due to fires at the time. We decided to give it another shot and it was well worth it. There was a long climb up to the top, and then a fast fun descent down. There were several creek crossings and some beautiful views, but you will just have to go check it out yourself to see it all.</p>

<p>We didnt get back to the trucks until just about dark, and then hurried into town to find the last place that was still open and had an ice cold PBR.</p>

<h4>Day 2: Kayaking the Ellensburg Canyon of the Yakima River</h4>

<p>I turned out to be a nice hot sunny day for a relaxing float. It was fun to get the river-level view of this familiar area. There was even a fun cliff jump part way through to make things a little more exciting.</p>

<p>We had planned to hike part of the PCT up near Mt. Rainier the next day so we headed up Chinook Pass to the park, but when we arrived, there was still several feet of snow on the ground. It was getting late, so we changed course and headed northwest instead to see what else we could find.</p>

<h4>Day 3: Hiking @ Mailbox Peak</h4>

<p>We ended up near North Bend so we decided to hike Mailbox Peak the next day. It was the Fourth of July so there were a few more people out than usual, but it was still a fun hike. For extra fun, we took the 'old trail' on the way back down.</p>

<p>
<figure>
<img src="/img/outdoors/sampler/mailbox.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Checking the mail at the top of Mailbox Peak<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure>
<img src="/img/outdoors/sampler/flag.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>'Murica<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure>
<img src="/img/outdoors/sampler/sunbeams.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Sunbeams on the old trail down<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<h4>Day 4: Kayaking @ Snoqualmie Falls / Mountain Biking @ Middle Fork Snoqualmie Trail</h4>

<p>The day started of kind of cloudy and grey, but it added to the peaceful nature of the morning float. We took out just above the roaring falls, and I would be lying if I said it wasnt a little disconcerting to paddle right up to the giant <strong>DANGER</strong> signs and see the very distinct horizon line as the falls plunged several hundred feet on the other side.</p>

<p>
<figure>
<img src="/img/outdoors/sampler/bike.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Waterfall along the Middle Fork Trail<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<h4>Day 5: Mountain Biking @ Duthie Hill</h4>

<p>We had been slowly snaking our way back toward Seattle and decided to finish off the trip with a day of mountain biking at Duthie Hill. There were lots of fun trails and not too many folks out, so we had a great time zipping around the berms and bumps.</p>

<hr />

<p>Previous Summer Adventures:</p>

<ul>
<li>2016 - <a href="/summer_adventure_john_wayne_pioneer_trail">John Wayne Pioneer Trail</a></li>
<li>2015 - <a href="/summer_adventure_paddle_to_the_sea">Paddle to the Sea</a></li>
<li>2014 - <a href="/summer_adventure_mountain_to_mountain">Mountain to Mountain</a></li>
<li>2013 - <a href="/summer_adventure_wambr">WaMBR Trail</a></li>
<li>2012 - <a href="/summer_olympics">Summer Olympics</a></li>
</ul>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jul 2017 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/summer_adventure_sampler</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/mailboxpeak_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Happy New Year 2017</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/new_years_2017</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_bikesunrise.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Happy New Year!</p>

<p>
<iframe width="740" height="416" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Ru6i86WaA80?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/new_years_2017</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_bikesunrise_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Summer Adventure - John Wayne Pioneer Trail</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/summer_adventure_john_wayne_pioneer_trail</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/jwpt.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>It is summer time now, so that means it is also Summer Adventure time. This year's adventure had been on my to-do list for a while: ride all the way across Washington on the (confusingly named) John Wayne/Pioneer/Iron Horse State Park Trail.</p>

<p>Chris met up with me in Seattle and we set out, quite literally across the street from my office building. From the Puget Sound, we would ride through Seattle and the outlying suburbs, up over Snoqualmie Pass, down to the Columbia River, and on across Eastern Washington all the way to the Idaho border just south of Spokane.</p>

<p>(I didnt take a ton of pictures because we were riding non-stop most of the time, but here are a few to give you an idea.)</p>

<p>We rode through Seattle that evening and camped out somewhere near Preston. The next morning, we were supposed to head towards Fall City, and our map indicated a possible bush-wacking route through the forest. We forged ahead but eventually came to an old decrepit railroad trestle that no longer spanned the gorge. We tried to bushwack down to the bottom and up again, but it was impassable. We wandered around for a couple of hours trying to find a way out without backtracking, and eventually found a super steep climb up to a golf course and a way out. Not recommended.</p>

<p>Once back on track, we made our way up to Rattlesnake Lake and the start of the old railroad bed that we would be following for the rest of the trip. We had a brief issue with Chris' bike (still kind of broken from our ill-fated <a href="/summer_adventure_wambr">WaMBR Trail</a> trip a couple of years back) but got it sorted and headed out. It was raining now as we pedalled slowly up the pass.</p>

<p>
<figure>
<img src="/img/outdoors/jwpt/jwpt1.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Heading out up over Snoqualmie Pass<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>As we rode, it started to rain harder and harder and we were drenched and cold. Eventually we go to the Snoqualmie Tunnel, the highlight of the entire trip. The 2.3 mile tunnel is completely dark, but it was also a welcome relief from the rain. Once through, we began our descent down the other side of the pass. By the time we reached Hyak, we were both chilled to the bone so we spent some time warming up before heading on. We rode around some beautiful lakes and ended up camping near Lake Easton.</p>

<p>The next morning we rode on and the sun came out as we pedalled along side the upper reaches of the Yakima River.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/jwpt/jwpt2.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Somewhere on the eastern slopes of the Cascades<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>We rode through Ellensburg and then on toward the Yakima Firing Range. This was supposed to be a tough section with no water and we were not allowed to stop (since it was an active firing range), so we stopped just short and camped for the night.</p>

<p>The next day, the ride through the firing range was actually quite fun. There were lots of rocks to avoid and some fun descents, and even a few more old decaying tunnels.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/jwpt/chris_tunnel2.gif" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Chris trying to decide to enter the scary tunnel or not<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/jwpt/jwpt3.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Railroad being reclaimed by nature<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>We reached the Columbia River and Chris decided that this trip was just too boring (we really just got up and pedalled on the same railroad bed every day, all day). Since we had a car waiting at the river anyway, we decided to end our trip before completing the eastern portion. Although he was right that it was a bit boring, I was still pretty bummed. Even though I wanted to keep going, I ended up earning the Lost Paddle Award<sup>™</sup> for planning a too-boring adventure this year.</p>

<p>Previous Summer Adventures:</p>

<ul>
<li>2015 - <a href="/summer_adventure_paddle_to_the_sea">Paddle to the Sea</a></li>
<li>2014 - <a href="/summer_adventure_mountain_to_mountain">Mountain to Mountain</a></li>
<li>2013 - <a href="/summer_adventure_wambr">WaMBR Trail</a></li>
<li>2012 - <a href="/summer_olympics">Summer Olympics</a></li>
</ul>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/summer_adventure_john_wayne_pioneer_trail</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/jwpt_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>My Year of Microadventures</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/year_of_microadventure</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_purpleflowers.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>At the beginning of this year, I decided that I was going to do at least one <a href="http://www.microadventures.org/">#microadventure</a> each month during 2015. There really werent any rules about it other than each adventure had to involve sleeping outside. I started out with a great overnight <a href="/wallace_falls_microadventure">hike at Wallace Falls</a> in January and a fun <a href="/goldmyer_hot_springs_microadventure">bike trip to Goldmyer Hot Springs</a> in February. There was also the big <a href="/summer_adventure_paddle_to_the_sea">Paddle to the Sea Summer Adventure</a> in July, but I didnt blog much about the other trips. I did however continue to get out each month and achieved my goal of an adventure every month.</p>

<p>The full list:</p>

<ul>
<li>January - Hiking at Wallace Falls</li>
<li>February - Biking at Goldmyer Hot Springs</li>
<li>March - Camping at Griffin Creek Natural Area</li>
<li>April - Kayak at Dugualla Bay</li>
<li>May - Hiking at Skyline Ridge</li>
<li>June - Camping at Baker Lake</li>
<li>July - Climbing, hiking, and kayaking from Mt. Baker to the sea</li>
<li>August - Hiking at Ozette Triangle</li>
<li>September - Camping in my own woods</li>
<li>October - Biking at Bainbridge Island</li>
<li>November - Kayaking at Deception Pass</li>
<li>December - Snow biking and snowshoeing at Nason Creek</li>
</ul>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/microadventure-calendar-2015.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/year_of_microadventure</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_purpleflowers_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Soup Box Derby 2015</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/soup_box_derby_2015</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/soupboxderby.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>After racing the <a href="/soup_box_derby_2010">kayak-strapped-to-two-bikes</a> for the <a href="/soup_box_derby_2014">past couple of years</a>, we decided to make some changes. This year we removed the kayak in favor of a couple of old office chairs and a cinder block. Not the prettiest machine out there, but definitely fun to build and race.</p>

<p><img src="/img/soupboxderby/2015.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p>
<iframe width="740" height="416" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/s8wnIxJWVf8?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

<p>As you can see in the clip above, we fell behind to the chicken racers early but just about caught up right at the finish line and lost by a hair. All in all, quite an entertaining way to spend a Sunday on Whidbey Island.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/soup_box_derby_2015</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/soupboxderby_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Backpacking the Ozette Triangle</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/ozette_triangle</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_ozettesunset.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Another adventure that had been on my list for a long time was backpacking along the Olympic coast, specifically the Ozette Triangle. This 9 mile round-trip hike starts off along a wooden boardwalk through the forest and then eventually drops down to the beach. From there, you walk along the beach for several miles, enjoying the rocky sea stacks, spotting wildlife, and killer sunsets. The trail then turns and heads back through the forest, completing the loop.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/ozettetriangle/map.png" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>Although this hike can be done pretty easily in a day, we wanted to make it into an overnight trip so we didnt head out until the afternoon and planned to camp along the beach about half-way through the loop.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/ozettetriangle/group.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>The whole group ready to head out</figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>The walk along the boardwalk was really fun and right as the crew was getting restless, the trees opened up and gave way to views of the open ocean. We dropped down to the beach and turned south.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/ozettetriangle/beach_walk.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Hiking along the beach<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>There were lots of neat rocks, logs, shells, pools, and more to explore. Speaking of logs, there were several places where we had to thread our way over and through some big driftwood piles, but everybody was having lots of fun.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/ozettetriangle/log.gif" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>You can do it!<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/ozettetriangle/sparkles.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Sun shimmering on the sea<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>It was great fun to walk along the beach, and as evening neared, we started to scout out a good campsite. We found a great spot on some higher ground and spent some time playing in the sand before being treated to an incredible sunset. We played cards and laughed and then enjoyed falling asleep staring up at the stars.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/ozettetriangle/sunset.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Pretty stunning sunset<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/ozettetriangle/camp.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Our camp for the night on some high ground<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>The next morning, things were pretty foggy and damp, but we started off with high spirits anyway. I had heard about some native hieroglyphic carvings on this part of the hike so we were on the look out.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/ozettetriangle/foggy.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Foggy morning beach trek<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>Eventually the skies cleared up and the sun came. We even found the hieroglyphics that we were looking for.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/ozettetriangle/reflections.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Beatiful sky colors reflecting in the tide pools<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/ozettetriangle/art.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Native hieroglyphics<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>Toward the end, Abbey was definitely getting cranky and ready to be done, but she trudged on with lots of coaxing. We finally arrived back at the starting point a few hours later than planned, but (almost) everyone had a great time.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/ozette_triangle</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_ozettesunset_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Summer Adventure - Paddle to the Sea</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/summer_adventure_paddle_to_the_sea</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_chrissilhouette.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>We finally had a successful summer adventure last year on our <a href="/summer_adventure_mountain_to_mountain">Mountain to Mountain</a> climb/bike/climb trip, so Chris and I were excited to cook up another crazy idea. I had been scouting out the area around Mt. Baker for awhile and decied that I thought we could link up a route all the way from the summit, essentially following the path of glacial run-off all the way to the ocean. So that is what we decided to do.</p>

<p>After dropping our car and kayaks in Concrete, WA and hitching a ride with some friends of Chris up to the Mt. Baker trailhead, we set out in the early evening. Our plan was to hike the approach and camp out at the top of the lateral moraine and then attempt the summit the next day.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/paddle_to_the_sea/baker_sunset.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Mt. Baker sunset<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>We woke up early and headed out. We were able to leave all of our camping stuff behind so we could travel much lighter.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/paddle_to_the_sea/chris_silhouette.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Chris' silhouette against Mt. Baker<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>We climbed and climbed, weaving around crevasses and dead-ends. We were a bit late in the season, so it was really warm and there were very few snow bridges. We eventually go up to about 8500 feet before we decided that the conditions just were not good for a summit push. We were a little bummed, but still had lots of adventure ahead of us.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/paddle_to_the_sea/chris_crevasse.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Chris crossing a crevasse<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>After we descended from Mt. Baker, it was a long dusty walk down from the trailhead. We camped out high above Baker Lake and would continue down to the lake and the next leg of the journey tomorrow.</p>

<p>The route down to the lake took us past an old abandoned dam, lots of incredible waterfalls, and an old abandoned power station that was covered in brush and moss - felt like stumbling upon a lost Inca ruin.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/paddle_to_the_sea/dam.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Derelict dam<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/paddle_to_the_sea/abandoned.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Abandoned power station<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>As we neared the bottom, we continued to follow the run-off right as it meandered into the lake.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/paddle_to_the_sea/chris_wading.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Chris wading the final stretch befor the lake<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>Once we arrived at the lake, it was time to break out the inflatable rafts. We only had to paddle about two miles down the lake to the dam where we would take out and walk to our kayaks.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/paddle_to_the_sea/one_man_raft.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>One-man raft<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>The rafts were a bit tiny and the paddling was a chore. Eventually the wind came up and was blowing so strong that we were literally having to paddle hard just to stay in place. At that rate, we would never make it down the lake, so we headed for shore to regroup. We tried walking along the shore, but many places were just rock cliffs or too thick with vegetation.</p>

<p>As time was slipping away and the wind only getting stronger, the waves were getting bigger and bigger and we decided that we needed to take more drastic action. We tried to hail a passing boat, but nearly everyone had already gotten off of the lake. Finally we were able to flag down a couple of guys who were out spraying weeds (Weed Board shout-out!) and they had a flatbed boat that they literally drove right up on the shore and rescued us.</p>

<p>Within minutes, we were down at the dam and profusely thanking them for their help. We packed up our rafts and started walking down into town where our kayaks awaited.</p>

<p>We switched gear and eddyed out into current of the Skagit River. The first day was just a couple of hours of paddling and then we made camp on a sandy beach.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/paddle_to_the_sea/kayak_camp.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Kayak camp on the banks of the Skagit<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/paddle_to_the_sea/chris_filtering.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Filtering water in the fading light<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>We paddled all day the next day and it was fun to see the landscape slowly change from forested wilderness into civilized suberbia as we neared the I-5 corridor. We had one more night of stealth kayak camping and then the next morning entered the marshy Skagit River delta.</p>

<p>It was a maze of channels but our navigation was spot-on and we eventually reached the rocky tide break wall where we would offically enter the sound.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/paddle_to_the_sea/hole.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Passing through a hole to the sea<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>After that, it was a short paddle up the Swinomish Channel to La Conner where we finished our trip. Other than a couple of small mishaps, it was another successful summer adventure.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/paddle_to_the_sea/end.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Smiling all the way to the end<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>Previous Summer Adventures:</p>

<ul>
<li>2014 - <a href="/summer_adventure_mountain_to_mountain">Mountain to Mountain</a></li>
<li>2013 - <a href="/summer_adventure_wambr">WaMBR Trail</a></li>
<li>2012 - <a href="/summer_olympics">Summer Olympics</a></li>
</ul>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/summer_adventure_paddle_to_the_sea</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_chrissilhouette_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Goldmyer Hot Springs #microadventure</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/goldmyer_hot_springs_microadventure</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/goldmyer.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>February's <a href="http://www.microadventures.org/">#microadventure</a> involved some hot springs out in the woods and had this simple formula:</p>

<ul>
<li>bike</li>
<li>soak</li>
<li>sleep</li>
<li>soak</li>
<li>bike</li>
</ul>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/goldmyer_bike.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/goldmyer_hot_springs_microadventure</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/goldmyer_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Wallace Falls #microadventure</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/wallace_falls_microadventure</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/stream.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>I am determined to get out for a <a href="http://www.microadventures.org/">#microadventure</a> each month during 2015 and even though I waited until the last day of the month, January's trip to Wallace Falls was a success. 11 more to go!</p>

<p>
<iframe width="740" height="416" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/v3k8tbbAG00?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2015 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/wallace_falls_microadventure</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/stream_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Fatbike Summer Meetup</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/fatbike_meetup</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/fatbikemeetup.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>I have been having a blast riding my Moonlander fatbike and even convinced Chris to get a bike of his own. Since the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/northwestfatbike">Northwest Fatbike</a> group was having their annual meetup in Ocean Shores, we loaded up and headed to the beach for a couple of days of riding with other like-minded folks.</p>

<p>
<figure>
<img src="/img/outdoors/fatbikemeetup/meetup1.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure>
<img src="/img/outdoors/fatbikemeetup/meetup2.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure>
<img src="/img/outdoors/fatbikemeetup/meetup3.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/fatbike_meetup</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/fatbikemeetup_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Soup Box Derby 2014</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/soup_box_derby_2014</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/soupboxderby.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Our Soup Box Derby racer was pulled out of retirement (and out of the weeds that had grown over it) for the 2014 race. We won two out of three of our heats, which isnt too bad for a couple of bikes we found on the side of the road, bolted together, and strapped a kayak on top of.</p>

<p>
<iframe width="280" height="497" style="display:inline;" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Wc0rDe9wn70?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>

<iframe width="280" height="497" style="display:inline;" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RSKYS0v9Uv4?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

<p><em>Nemo's Nemesis</em> has now officially been retired and we will be back with an all-new racer next year!</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/soup_box_derby_2014</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/soupboxderby_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Whidbey Triathlon</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/whidbey_triathlon</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/tri.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Second time doing the Whidbey Triathlon this past weekend. A few minutes slower than last year, but had a good time as always.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/tri2014.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2014 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/whidbey_triathlon</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/tri_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Summer Adventure - Mountain to Mountain</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/summer_adventure_mountain_to_mountain</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/mt_to_mt.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>This year's Summer Adventure idea was cooked up by Chris: how about we climb Mt. Adams, mountain bike over to Mt. St. Helens, and climb that as well?</p>

<p>After the last couple of adventures and too many Lost Paddle Awards<sup>™</sup> to list, I was definitely worried about our chances of success. But in the end, we didn't have any (major) issues, completed the entire adventure, and even had a little bit of fun doing it.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/mt_to_mt/adams_depart.jpg" class="largeimg"  />
<figcaption>Heading out for the climb up Mt. Adams<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/mt_to_mt/approach.jpg" class="largeimg"  />
<figcaption>First stop: top of that mountain<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/mt_to_mt/sunset1.jpg" class="largeimg"  />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/mt_to_mt/sunset2.jpg" class="largeimg"  />
<figcaption>Sunset on the flanks of Mt. Adams<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/mt_to_mt/summit_adams.jpg" class="largeimg"  />
<figcaption>On top of Mt. Adams<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/mt_to_mt/sthelens.jpg" class="largeimg"  />
<figcaption>View of Mt. St. Helens from the summit of Mt. Adams<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/mt_to_mt/bike_depart.jpg" class="largeimg"  />
<figcaption>Back down - heading out on the bikes<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/mt_to_mt/bike.jpg" class="largeimg"  />
<figcaption>Somewhere in the Dark Divide<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/mt_to_mt/adams.jpg" class="largeimg"  />
<figcaption>View of Mt. Adams from the summit of Mt. St. Helens<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>Previous Summer Adventures:</p>

<ul>
<li>2013 - <a href="/summer_adventure_wambr">WaMBR Trail</a></li>
<li>2012 - <a href="/summer_olympics">Summer Olympics</a></li>
</ul>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2014 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/summer_adventure_mountain_to_mountain</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/mt_to_mt_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kulshan Quest</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/kulshan_quest</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/kulshanquest.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>The folks that put on the San Juan Island Quest adventure race that <a href="/san_juan_island_quest">I did a few years ago</a> had a new race in Bellingham this year called the Kulshan Quest. Six hours of kayaking, biking, and trekking in the waters and woods near Chuckanut Bay on a gorgeous summer solstice day - can't really beat that!</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/kulshanquest/kayak.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/kulshanquest/trekking.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/kulshanquest/biking.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2014 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/kulshan_quest</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/kulshanquest_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>March Microadventure - Bateman Island</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/bateman_island_overnight</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bateman_island.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Starting a new job caused me to miss a #microadventue in February so I was determined to get out during March. Big thanks to Chris for coming up with a great idea on short notice. A little stealth camping on an island only a stones throw from the shopping mall was a great way to spend a night under the stars.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/bateman_island.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/bateman_island_overnight</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bateman_island_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Walla Walla Dirty Duathlon</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/walla_walla_dirty_duathlon</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/wwdd.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Chris found out about an interesting-sounding event down in Walla Walla called the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/WallaWallaDirtyDuathlon/">Dirty Duathlon</a>. It consists of running 2.7 miles, biking 15.4 miles, then running the same 2.7 miles again. I headed over to the Tri-Cities to meet up with Chris and we headed down.</p>

<p>Prior to the race, it had been pouring rain, and even as we were checking in, it was coming down in sheets. The race must go on though, and we took off into what had become a giant muddy mess.</p>

<p>No photos from during the actual race, but you can see the after affects from these photos:</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/wwdd/bikes.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/wwdd/crank.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/wwdd/defailleur.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/wwdd/dirtyface.jpg" class="smallimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/wwdd/dirtylegs.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/wwdd/smiling.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>In the end, we still had smiles on our faces behind all of the mud.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/walla_walla_dirty_duathlon</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/wwdd_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New Year, New Adventures</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/new_year_new_adventures</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_deceptionpasssunset.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Continuing the theme from last year, I am trying to sneak in one #microadventure each month. This month, I didn't have to travel too far from home to find a completely secluded spot. Even though I could see Deception Pass bridge in the distance, my special spot ensured that there were no other folks around and anybody who wants to have this same view will have to work for it a bit.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/deceptionpasssunset.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p>A beautiful sunset followed by a crystal clear night under the stars is definitely not the worst way to spend a cool January night. Why not get out there and have a little <a href="http://www.microadventures.org/">microadventure</a> of your own?</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/new_year_new_adventures</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_deceptionpasssunset_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>December Microadventure - Snow Bike + Camp</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/snow_bike_overnight</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bikesled.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Take one bike with fat tires, add one kid's sled, sprinkle in a generous helping of snow and you have yourself one mighty fine little overnight adventure.</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/rpn-zBl6iik?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/snow_bike_overnight</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bikesled_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Global Fatbike Day</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/global_fatbike_day</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_bikesunbeams.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Did you get out and ride your fatbike for Global Fat Bike Day? What's that? You didn't know it was Global Fat Bike Day? And you don't have a fatbike to ride? Sheesh! Well, I got out and had a fun ride, so you can live vicariously through me.</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/OCC0ZwqlcJs?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/global_fatbike_day</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_bikesunbeams_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>October Microadventure - Close to Home</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/close_to_home</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/darkfire.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>For October's microadventure, I decided to keep it close to home. Very close.</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/igN_D7V59WE?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/close_to_home</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/darkfire_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Front Yard Timelapse</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/front_yard_timelapse</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/frontyard.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>How to turn 32,000 pounds of rocks into a beautiful retaining wall:</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/front1.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/front2.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/front3.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/front4.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p>And once the rock wall was complete, it was time to turn our attention to the grass. It took us a lot of hard work, but you can enjoy it all in just two quick minutes:</p>

<p>
<iframe width="740" height="416" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iG3isjHWB8Y?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/front_yard_timelapse</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/frontyard_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Grand Canyon Rim to Rim</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/grand_canyon</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/grandcanyon.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>I moved to Arizona in 1999 and had big ideas of hiking the Grand Canyon as much as time would allow. Well, I moved away from Arizona in 2006 and never visited the Grand Canyon a single time.</p>

<p>Fast-forward several years though and Chris suggested we take a long weekend and hike the canyon from rim to rim. Sounded like a great idea to me, so we flew out, rented a car, and drove up to the south rim.</p>

<p>The next morning, we took a shuttle around to the north rim and began our hike. It was really an amazing hike and fun to keep descending into the canyon deeper and deeper.</p>

<p>We intended to stay over night at the bottom of the canyon and hike out the next day, but that is where things took a turn for the worse. I ended up getting very very sick (perhaps food poisioning) and was up all night vomiting. We still had to hike from the base up to the rim though, so we packed up and headed out - me making pit stops every 15 minutes or so to throw up. =(</p>

<p>At one of the ranger stations on the way out, one of the rangers said I really did not look well and suggested we stay there for a bit. They gave me some anti-nausea pills and I took a nap for a couple of hours. Once rested, I still didnt feel great, but we donned our packs once again and hike up and out.</p>

<p>Even with the sickness, it was a great trip and I hope to go back someday and do it again - minus the vomiting.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/grandcanyon.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Chris and I on the North Rim at the start of our hike<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/grand_canyon</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/grandcanyon_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Summer Adventure - WaMBR Trail</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/summer_adventure_wambr</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/wambr.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>After last year's [Summer Olympics][SummerOlympics] trip, Chris and I decided to make it an annual tradition to go on a hair-brained adventure. This year I wanted to go map and ride the WaMBR Trail - a mountain bike route that I hoped would span the entire length of the state from Canada to Oregon.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/wambr/boundary.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>US-Canada Border - An unlawful crossing<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/wambr/cemetary.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Old cemetary site<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/wambr/mine.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Abandoned mine<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/wambr/chris.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Chris and some of the rocks that would be his downfall<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/wambr/wambr.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Somewhere deep on the WaMBR Trail<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>Unfortunately, we only made it a day and a half before everything fell apart. Like literally, Chris' rear axle fell apart and he had to walk back to the car and drive into town to get a repair. Meanwhile, I kept going but quickly discovered that the proposed route was a literal dead-end at a deep ravine.</p>

<p>After much map consulting, we realized that the route just wasnt going to work. The dream of the WaMBR Trail was dead. =(</p>

<p>We regrouped and did end up riding the <a href="https://www.mtbproject.com/trail/7014007/blue-buck-trail-421">Blue Buck Trail</a> instead. It was overgrown, exposed, wet, and sometimes barely there, but it was still a really fun adventure.</p>

<p>Although the whole ill-fated trail was my idea, Chris' broken bike on the second day earned him the Lost Paddle Award<sup>™</sup> again this year.</p>

<p>Previous Summer Adventures:</p>

<ul>
<li>2012 - <a href="/summer_olympics">Summer Olympics</a></li>
</ul>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/summer_adventure_wambr</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/wambr_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>June Microadventure - Horse Heaven Hills Bike Overnight</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/horse_heaven_hills_bike</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/horseheavenbikes.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Chris and I have a big bike adventure coming up in July (riding and mapping out the WaMBR Trail) so we decided to do a shorter overnight trip to test out some gear and work out any kinks.</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KEqykNXkrBc?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

<p>We started at the top of Lincoln Grade in Prosser and pretty much rode due East, staying right along the edge of the ridgeline that runs high above the Yakima River valley. Some of it was dirt roads, some of it was skirting the edge of wheat fields, and some of it was just straight cross-country over sagebrush and cheatgrass. We slept under the stars (and some microwave towers) and when we eventually ran out of ridgeline, we dropped down to the canal bank and rode all the way back to his house. Chris put the route info online and generated the map and elevation profile below.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/track.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>It turned out to be a really fun ride and definitely got me excited for our bigger trip coming up next month.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/horse_heaven_hills_bike</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/horseheavenbikes_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>#30DaysOfBiking</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/30_days_of_biking</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_beachbikesolitude.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>About a month ago, I heard about a challenge called <a href="http://30daysofbiking.com/">30 Days of Biking</a>. It is just what it sounds like: you ride your bike every day for 30 days straight during the month of April. I thought is sounded like fun, so I decided to take part.</p>

<p>I have to confess that I did skip two days while I was sick, but I did go for some extra rides on other days to make up for it. Each day, I took a picture during my ride and now that the challenge is over, I decided to compile the pictures into a single image that represents the entire month.</p>

<p>
<figure>
<img src="/img/outdoors/30dob.jpg" class="smallimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>I tried to explore new places and not get stuck in a routine of the same old rides, which made it really fun to get out and ride each day. The official #30DaysOfBiking only takes place once a year, but why wait? Get out there and start riding your bike today!</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/30_days_of_biking</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_beachbikesolitude_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>April Microadventure - Whidbey Fatbike Beach Ride</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/whidbey_fatbike_beach_ride</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bikebeachcamp.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>The adventure for April was an overnight bike beach ride. I rode down the western shore of Whidbey Island, camped out under a super bright full moon, and just generally had a fun time on my monster bike.</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8hx_Hbw4qo0?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/whidbey_fatbike_beach_ride</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bikebeachcamp_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>March Microadventure - Whidbey to Camano Paddle</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/whidbey_to_camano_paddle</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/camanopaddle.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>April is nearly over but I realized that I never posted about my March #microadventure. I paddled from Whidbey across Saratoga Passage over to Camano Island State Park. It was great weather (especially for March) and I spent most of the time just lounging around on the beach. I camped out overnight and paddled back the next day for a very relaxing and enjoyable quick trip.</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vrwmtQI9YRA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/whidbey_to_camano_paddle</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/camanopaddle_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lanham Lake Snowshoe</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/lanham_lake_snowshoe</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/lanhamlake.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Inspired by <a href="http://www.alastairhumphreys.com/microadventures-3/">Alastair Humphrey's idea of microadventures</a>, I decided I would try to do a small adventure once every month in 2013. Well, January came and went and I didnt do anything - not a great start. February was quickly passing as well and eventually I found myself on the last day of the month and I still hadnt done a thing. That just wouldnt do though, so I decided I better get out there before the month completely passed me by.</p>

<p>Since it is wintertime here in the Pacific Northwest, I wanted to take advantage of the snow. I planned to snowshoe and camp up at Artist Point, near Mt. Baker. However, a bunch of warm weather and rain had caused the avalanche danger to increase significantly. Not to be deterred, I pulled out my copy of [Snowshoe Routes - Washington][ShowshoeRoutes] to look for an alternative. Lanham Lake near Stevens Pass stood out as a nice short trip with a great little lake to camp at and virtually no avalanche danger. So I hopped in my truck and headed out.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/lanhamlake/creek.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The avalanche danger still caught up with me though, albeit in a different way. The WA Department of Transportation was going to be closing Stevens Pass at 2pm to do avalanche control work. The closure could last up to 4 hours, which would mean zero daylight for the hike. I was in Everett at 12:30, so I knew I would be cutting it close, but as the mile markers passed, it looked like I might just make it. I knew the closure was at milepost 58 and as I passed milepost 57, I still had 2 minutes to spare. However, just up ahead, I could see some flashing lights and a few cars already stopped in the road. Just missed it by literally a minuter or so, so I spent the next two hours sitting and waiting.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/lanhamlake/forest.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>When the road finally opened and I got to the trailhead, It was almost 5pm. Darkness comes early in the winter here, but the days have been getting ever so slightly longer lately so I headed out. I crested the first rise with little daylight to spare and an hour or so in, it was getting dark quickly. I pulled out my headlamp and continued on - snowshoeing through the snow-covered forest with no one around in total darkness was very serene and peaceful. Finally, the rain that had been threatening all day started to come down, and come down hard.</p>

<p>I found a nice spot just off the trail and tramped down a flat area for my tent. I melted some snow and boiled up some ramen noodles, but the rain was really coming down hard so I had to eat quickly and take refuge in my tent. All night, the rain poured and wet snow dripped off of the trees.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/lanhamlake/lake.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>By morning, everything was soaked so I tore down camp quickly without eating breakfast. I continued a short ways up the trail to the actual shore of the lake to have a look around. The snow covered lake was perfectly still. I hadnt seen anyone or any sign of tracks at all, so I had the place to myself. After taking in the views for a bit, I turned around and headed back out. The rain was still falling, but not quite as hard. I made quick work of the downhill return trip and was back at my truck around 10am - just about 24 hours after setting out.</p>

<p>Due to the fading light and pouring rain, I didnt get many photos or video, but here is a very short glimpse of the trip.</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BqGFvP4CHQA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2013 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/lanham_lake_snowshoe</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/lanhamlake_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>San Juan Island Quest</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/san_juan_island_quest</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/sanjuanislandquest.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>After about a seven year hiatus, I competed in another adventure race this past Saturday. I saw a actually saw poster for the <a href="http://www.sanjuanislandquest.com/">San Juan Island Quest</a> while riding the ferry and thought it sounded like fun. Although they offered a 12-hour course as well, I decided that the 6-hour course was a better idea, so I signed up, loaded up my truck, and headed over to beautiful Orcas Island.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuanadventurerace2012/sign_zps4070fa7f.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Race Headquarters<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuanadventurerace2012/bike_zps7de6ec85.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>My bike getting ready for the event<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuanadventurerace2012/racers_zpsb7a6f5fb.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>The competition milling about<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>After a bit of delay, we got started at 12:15. First off was the mountain biking leg, which required a long, steep climb and then some fast, fun downhill. Unfortunately, it seemed like more up than down to me, but it was a beautiful area and I couldnt complain at all.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuanadventurerace2012/checkpoint_zps163c324f.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Checkpoint #2<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>Then it was on to the kayaking. The sun was just coming out and the water was smooth as glass. Great day to be out on the lake paddling.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuanadventurerace2012/kayak2_zps9346809a.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Just completed the kayaking leg<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>After a short bike back to the HQ, it was off to the trekking portion. I am not a runner, but I used some good navigation to pick up a few places by being smart instead of fast.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuanadventurerace2012/waterfall_zpsa3c1b8e5.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Cascade Falls<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuanadventurerace2012/sunriserock_zpscf810942.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Atop Sunrise Rock<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>After the last checkpoint, we had to canoe a couple hundred yards and then return to the finish line. I came in around 6:25pm or so, putting me just barely over the 6-hour mark. Out of 14 teams, I came 7th, which I was pretty happy with. (The guy who won runs ultra-marathons in the Alps for a hobby, so I didnt feel too bad).</p>

<p>Anyway, it was a great course, beautiful day, and overall fun event. Definitely planning on doing it again next year!</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Sep 2012 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/san_juan_island_quest</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/sanjuanislandquest_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>RIP Rob</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/rob_graff</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/robgraff.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Hope you found the peace that eluded you in life.</p>

<p><img src="/img/other/rob2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/other/rob1.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Aug 2012 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/rob_graff</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/robgraff_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Splashy Fun on the Sauk</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/splashy_fun_on_the_sauk</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_sideyak.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Got out kayaking on the middle section (Whitechuck to Backman Park) of the Sauk this past Saturday and it was a great time. Beautiful sunny day and fun whitewater - not the worst way to spend the day!</p>

<p><em>(You can see me flip just after 4 minutes in, and the best whitewater is about 5 minutes in if you are just looking for the good stuff).</em></p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/7Y8daLTuXfQ?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2012 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/splashy_fun_on_the_sauk</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_sideyak_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Summer Olympics</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/summer_olympics</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bearcamp.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Well, this summer's big adventure was to be a 116 mile traverse of the entire Olympic Peninsula by foot and boat. Things didnt quite go as planned, but we still had a good time anyway. Here is a glimpse of what we saw and how things turned out:</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pcCVvNE8eVw?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

<p>This is the origins of the Lost Paddle Award<sup>™</sup> that would wind up becoming a bit of an unfortunate theme for future adventures.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jul 2012 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/summer_olympics</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bearcamp_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kayak Camping in the San Juans</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/kayaking_san_juan_islands</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_kayakcove.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>I met Doug during the <a href="/nwoc_whitewater_class">NWOC whitewater kayaking class</a> a couple of years back and we had done some whitewater kayaking together. He was more into sea kayaking though, so we decided to do an overnight trip to explore some of the San Juan islands.</p>

<p>We launched from Washington Park in Anacortes and headed across the Guemes Channel. We skirted along Cypress Island and eventually made our way over to the tiny Strawberry Island where we found a sheltered cove and we went ashore for lunch. It was really fun having the entire island to ourselves and looking out over the ocean and other islands in the distance.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuankayak/rockycove.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Rocky cove on Strawberry Island<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>After lunch, we headed west toward Blakely Island and then turned south towards Decatur Island and James Island. The currents on the west side of James Island were flowing very strong and it was fun and exhilarating to try to manuever in them.</p>

<p>James Island is entirely a state park with boat-only access and a great Cascadia Marine Trail campsite and was our destination for the night. The campsite sat high above a nice beach with great views of the surrounding area.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuankayak/sign.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>The well-marked campsite<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuankayak/stairs.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Stairs from the beach to the campsite<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuankayak/tents.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Home for the night<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>We had plenty of day left so we hiked around the island to check it out. There was another campsite on the other side of the island and lots of great views.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuankayak/view1.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuankayak/view2.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuankayak/view3.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuankayak/view4.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/sanjuankayak/from_on_high.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>View of our kayaks from on high<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>The next morning we had a leisurely breakfast and then headed out. We paddled due east across the Rosario Straight and encountered a minke whale and some giant container barges heading out to sea. Once across, we explored the tide pools along the western edge of Fidalgo Island before returning to our stating point.</p>

<p>The weather was gorgeous and it was a super fun trip. Definitely need to get out and paddle this area some more.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2012 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/kayaking_san_juan_islands</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_kayakcove_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kayaking the Lower Green Gorge</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/kayaking_lower_green_gorge</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/greenrivergorge.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Got out this past Saturday for some cold-weather kayaking. This was my first time taking video while kayaking so it is not the most exciting video, but still gives a sense of how beautiful the scenery is.</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PHBJeoOwXVM?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/kayaking_lower_green_gorge</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/greenrivergorge_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New Sport - Si-yaking</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/siyaking</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_sideyak.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Here I am inventing a new sport - sideways kayaking, or si-yaking for short. It is just like normal kayaking, but tilted 90° for more full-water contact.</p>

<p><p><img src="/img/outdoors/siyaking.jpg"></p>

<p>Si-yaking is often also paired with another fun sport: whitewater swimming =)</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 04 Nov 2011 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/siyaking</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_sideyak_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Married</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/wedding</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_wedding.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Michaleen and I got engaged at the end of our <a href="/buckskin_gulch">Buckskin Gulch hiking trip</a> and today we are officially married! Close family and lots of good food made it a wonderful day.</p>

<p><img src="/img/other/wedding.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2011 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/wedding</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_wedding_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kayak Roll Practice</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/kayak_roll_practice</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_sideyak.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Been heading over to Deer Lake for some kayak rolling practice. Yesterday I got my StickPod camera mount in the mail, so I decided to try it out:</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/hZEtICoogm8?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2011 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/kayak_roll_practice</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_sideyak_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Climbing Mt. St. Helens</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/climbing_mt_st_helens_2</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/mtsthelens.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Didn't make the summit <a href="/climbing_mt_st_helens_1">last year due to whiteout conditions</a>, but returned this year with Chris, Andy, Conner, and Zack to try again. Windy, rainy, cloudy weather made for a long cold day, but everyone reached the summit and (hopefully) had a good time.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtsthelenssummit.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2011 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/climbing_mt_st_helens_2</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/mtsthelens_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>4 + 1 = 1</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/raccooned</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/rip.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>4 chickens + 1 raccoon = 1 chicken =(</p>

<p>RIP Penny, Dominique, &amp; Alfonso</p>

<p><img src="/img/chickens/rip.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2011 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/raccooned</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/rip_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Buckskin Gulch</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/buckskin_gulch</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/buckskingulch.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Along with our visit to Arizona last week, part of our trip was also geared around our hike of <a href="http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;q=buckskin+gulch">Buckskin Gulch</a>. It is considered one of the longest slot canyons in the world, and I had been looking forward to doing this hike for some time. As the day got closer, the weather was looking worse and worse (and being in the bottom of a 400-foot deep, 5-foot wide canyon is not the place you want to be when a rain storm sets in), so I was very worried we would have to cancel our hike.</p>

<p>In the end however, the weather held out and we had a great time. The pictures really don't do it justice - it was one of the best trips I have ever been on.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000364.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000367.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000372.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000374.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000376.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000378.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000380.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000381.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000384.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000385.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000388.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000389.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000364.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000391.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000392.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000394.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000396.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000397.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000400.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000402.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000404.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000405.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000407.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000410.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000413.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000416.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000422.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000425.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000426.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000429.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000430.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000433.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000435.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000436.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000441.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/buckskingulch/P1000442.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Here is a short video showing a particularly narrow spot:</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/PMnZSqJooaE?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/buckskin_gulch</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/buckskingulch_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hiking @ Goose Rock</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/goose_rock_hike</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/gooserock.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>We all got out for a great hike at Deception Pass. Goose Rock is the highest point in the park, and on all of Whidbey Island. We started near the bridge and looped around the waters edge then climbed up to the top before descending back down the other side. It was a beautiful day and there were loads of smiles all around.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gooserock/path.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>The path ahead<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gooserock/bay.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Looking across the bay<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gooserock/yellow.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption><figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gooserock/weirdtree.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption><figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gooserock/fungus.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption><figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gooserock/moss.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption><figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gooserock/fromthetop.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>The viwe from the top<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gooserock/eden.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Eden pondering the cosmos<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gooserock/bridge.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Bridge crossing<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gooserock/leading.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Leading the way<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gooserock/where.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Where did they go?<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gooserock/inatree.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>I can climb this tree too<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gooserock/deadly.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Try not to do that<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2011 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/goose_rock_hike</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/gooserock_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Rolling Huts</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/rolling_huts</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/rollinghuts.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>We headed up to Winthrop last weekend to spend some time at the <a href="http://www.rollinghuts.com">Rolling Huts</a> and play in the snow. We did some snowshoeing and some ice skating, played some games, read some ghost stories, and just generally had a good time.</p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000247.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000251.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000252.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000254.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000255.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000260.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000261.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000263.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000264.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000266.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000268.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000269.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000271.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000272.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/rollinghuts/P1000274.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2011 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/rolling_huts</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/rollinghuts_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Great Chicken Coop Fire of 2010</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/great_chicken_coop_fire</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/coop_fire.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Before:</p>

<p><img src="/img/chickens/before.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>After:</p>

<p><img src="/img/chickens/after.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Luckily all of the chickens made it out safely.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2010 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/great_chicken_coop_fire</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/coop_fire_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Soup Box Derby 2010</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/soup_box_derby_2010</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/soupboxderby.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Langley's Soup Box Derby was this past weekend, and after a few years of <em>intending</em> to participate, we finally got in gear and built our racer.</p>

<p>After scoring a couple of old (free!) BMX bikes to use as the base, an idea took shape. Michaleen and I spent Friday afternoon and evening putting the contraption together, and, after an ill-fated attempt at some rear-wheel steering, had a complete (albeit untested) racer done at 10pm. With darkness upon us, we had to cancel any plans for a test run and just hope for the best at the race in the morning.</p>

<p><img src="/img/soupboxderby/ondisplay.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Here it is in all of its glory: two bikes hooked together with some metal bits with a kayak strapped on top - the pinnacle of simplicity and elegance!</p>

<p><img src="/img/soupboxderby/ondisplay2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Michaleen suggested that if everything went horribly wrong and I couldnt stop the contraption, I could veer left and into Puget Sound, so we dediced the paddle was a necessity.</p>

<p><img src="/img/soupboxderby/pitcrew.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Here is me with 3/4ths of the pit crew preparing for the first run.</p>

<p><img src="/img/soupboxderby/testrun.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Each racer had to take a mandatory solo test run to make sure their machine was capable. Since we have never tested out our contraption, I have to admit I was a bit nervous. After about 10 yards, I picked up some steam and suddenly had quite a bit of shaking and wobbling to contend with. I managed to keep the racer inbetween the curbs, but something was definitely wrong.</p>

<p><img src="/img/soupboxderby/advice.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>After the test run, we decided that the shaking and jerking was due to too much toe-out and some loose handlebar bolts. We neglected to bring any tools, but after a quick trip to the second-hand store, we had a make-shift tool make out of a socket bit (no ratchet) and decided that our problems were solved and we were going to go for it. Here is Eden giving me some advice on how to improve my driving for the official runs.</p>

<p><img src="/img/soupboxderby/winning.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>We headed back up the hill and the official came over and offered some cautionary words. He was worried about the shaking and swerving, but I assured him we were sorted. Even the little kids were making the run from the top of the hill so we couldnt wimp out now. In the first heat, I started of cautiously with the brakes slightly on just in case. As my competitior pulled ahead, I decided to just go for it. Miraculously, the shakes were gone and I navigated straight and true to the finish a few yards behind.</p>

<p><img src="/img/soupboxderby/action.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>In the second heat, I was feeling more confident and went for it as soon as the flag dropped. Our well-tuned machine pulled away from the competition and cruised to victory.</p>

<p><img src="/img/soupboxderby/trophy.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>In the end, we werent the fastest racer, but we werent even close to the slowest, so I was happy. For our outstanding effort, we 'earned' these trophies. Actually, everybody who entered and even some people who didnt enter got a trophy. In the end, it was a really fun day and we are already dreaming up ideas for next years vehicle.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/soup_box_derby_2010</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/soupboxderby_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Summer Projects</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/summer_projects</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/summer_projects.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Finally got a couple of summer projects wrapped up so I decided to share a few pictures.</p>

<p><img src="/img/chickens/coop.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>First up is the chicken coop/chicken run. In just five short months, the chickens have grown from being small enough to hold in your hand to practically full grown.</p>

<p>The chickens just started laying eggs as well - first one chicken followed the next day by another. Almost two weeks went by before the third started as well, and we are still waiting on the fourth. So far they have produced almost two dozen eggs though, and we are consistently getting three eggs every day now. If you have never had them, I cant recommend farm-raised fresh chicken eggs enough - they taste 100 times better than store-bought.</p>

<p><img src="/img/chickens/shed.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The chicken coop is attached to the garden shed, which is actually more like a covered storage area since it only has walls on three sides and most of those walls are just windows or fencing.</p>

<p>We got the steel casement windows from a guy here on the island who was saving them for an art project. He finally decided he wasnt going to get around to it, so we took them off his hands. The windows in the roof came from a local antique store, and all in all, I think it turned out really nice.</p>

<p><img src="/img/chickens/garden_bed.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/chickens/garden_bare.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/chickens/garden.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Lastly, the vegetable garden. We didnt really know what we were doing, so we decided just to plant everything we wanted and see how it went. Some of the plants should have been planted in the fall or started indoors, but we still had pretty good success. A few things didnt grow (I am looking at you, watermelon and butternut squash), but almost everything else did well.</p>

<p>The first thing to come up was the lettuce and though we ate some, it turned out to be very popular with the chickens. Abbey even gets them to jump for the lettuce, which is pretty funny to watch. The chickens also love the broccoli leaves and fava beans, though we are saving most of the fava beans for ourselves (homemade pasta with fava beans and pancetta is my new favorite).</p>

<p>Another surprise was the potatoes - we planted three varieties (german butterball, russian banana, and purple peruvian) and they did amazing. In just a few months, we have tons of big potatoes. The german butterball potatoes are so good - you gotta try them!</p>

<p>Right now, the various summer squash plants are taking over the garden, but we are still waiting on some beans, leeks, jalapenos, and a few other things as well.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Aug 2010 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/summer_projects</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/summer_projects_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Cracked Frame with a Happy Ending</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/cracked_frame</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_bikesunbeams.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Before...</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/bike/whole_bike.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/bike/crack_from_side.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/bike/crack_from_side.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>After...</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/bike/red2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/bike/red1.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2010 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/cracked_frame</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_bikesunbeams_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>NWOC Total Immersion Whitewater Class</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/nwoc_whitewater_class</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/nwoc.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>I love living on an island and the plentiful sea kayaking opportunities, but I really wanted to start whitewater kayaking as well. I signed up for a week long total-immersion class with Northwest Outdoor Center and it was a blast. I learned a lot and just generally had a super fun time. Highly recommended!</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/nwoc/kayak.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/nwoc/kayak2.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/nwoc/kayak3.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2010 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/nwoc_whitewater_class</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/nwoc_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Gorge Waterfalls</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/gorge_waterfalls</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/gorge.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>There are lots and lots of waterfalls in the Columbia Gorge, and we got out to check a few of them out. A beautiful place to explore for sure.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gorge/headedout.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Headed out - off to a beautiful start<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gorge/waterfall1.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gorge/waterfall2.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gorge/waterfall3.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/gorge/waterfall4.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2010 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/gorge_waterfalls</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/gorge_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Climbing Mt. St. Helens</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/climbing_mt_st_helens_1</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/mtsthelens.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>I wanted to try a springtime ascent of Mt. St. Helens and do some snowshoeing in the process, so I headed out in late April to do a little overnight trip. The route is different than the summertime route and follows the 'Worm Flows' route instead.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtsthelens/map.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtsthelens/brian.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p>I snowshoed in a ways and made camp for the night. I had my tent and my stove and a nice protected spot and settled right in.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtsthelens/camp.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p>Although the weather had been great for my approach, the next day the weather started getting worse and worse. As I neared the summit, it turned into full-on whiteout conditions and I couldnt tell the ground from the sky or which way was up. I sat and tried to wait it out, but it just kept getting wetter and windier so I finally turned around feeling a little defeated. I will be back to try again next year though.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtsthelens/mountain.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Apr 2010 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/climbing_mt_st_helens_1</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/mtsthelens_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Chicks</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/chicks</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/chicks.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p><img src="/img/chickens/chicks.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Four new additions to the family recently</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2010 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/chicks</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/chicks_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Sledding @ Big Four Ice Caves</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/sledding_at_big_four_ice_caves</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/sledding_ice_caves.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>I had been wanting to take everyone sledding this winter, and this past weekend we finally got the chance. The original plan was to head to Mt. Pilchuck and the Heather Lake trailhead, where they closed the road and set up a Winter Recreation Area just for sledding and snowshoeing. However, when we arrived, there was not a trace of snow anywhere. We followed the road 7 more miles to the Mt. Pilchuck trailhead and still not a patch of snow to be seen. Hmmm - we had driven this far, we didnt want to go home empty-handed.</p>

<p>We head back down the hill and stopped at the Verlot Vistor Center to ask the rangers their advice on where to go. Unfortunately, they told us what we already knew - there was no snow anywhere nearby. Finally, one of them suggested we try the Big Four Ice Caves area - there might be a small bit of snow left there, but it was a bit of a hike in and no guarantees. It was better than driving home defeated, so we decided to give it a try.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/icecavesledding/start.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The hike in was about a mile through a very pretty area. The start consisted of a wooden boardwalk across a beaver marsh, and then a crossing of the Stillaguamish River before leading to the ice caves. The surrounding snow was completely gone, but the actual ice caves themselves were still there. With the fog and the granite backdrop, it was quite an impressive sight.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/icecavesledding/approaching.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/icecavesledding/cave.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/icecavesledding/fog2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/icecavesledding/fog.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>We found a small place off to the side suitable for sledding. The snow was very hard, but we were able to carve out a couple of small chutes. The rides were short and bumpy, but everyone had a great time anyway.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/icecavesledding/teganabbey.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/icecavesledding/michaleen.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/icecavesledding/sledding.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Although not at all how we inteded the trip to go, we had a great time in a beautiful place that we probably would not have even known was there otherwise. A truly fortuitous turn of events and a flexible attitude by everyone made for a great trip in the end.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2010 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/sledding_at_big_four_ice_caves</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/sledding_ice_caves_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Snowshoeing @ Skyline Lake</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/snowshoeing_at_skyline</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/skyline_lake.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>This past weekend, we decided to take advantage of the winter weather and do some snowshoeing. We decided on a spot up [at Stevens Pass<a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?hl=en&amp;q=Stevens+Pass,+Leavenworth,+WA+98826&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hq=&amp;hnear=Stevens+Pass,+Leavenworth,+Chelan,+Washington+98826&amp;ll=47.75127,-121.090879&amp;spn=0.021092,0.038195&amp;t=h&amp;z=15">Map</a> that offered a short 3-mile round-trip trek with a lake at the top.</p>

<p>When we arrived, it was overcast, windy, and downright chilly. But we bundled up and headed out anyway. However, not too far into the trek, the sun came out and we had beautiful blue skies.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skylinesnowshoe/headingout.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The trek was entirely uphill for the first half (in order to gain the ridge and reach the lake), but everyone trudged onward.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skylinesnowshoe/longhill.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Near the top, the trail forked and we initally took the right path. this lead to a beautiful view of the surrounding area.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skylinesnowshoe/atthetop.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>After taking in the views, we retreated downhill several hundred yards and then took the left path to the lake. It was completely frozen over and snow covered with lots of tracks right across the middle of it.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skylinesnowshoe/atthelake.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>A nearby small peak called out to be climbed, but we decided to eat our lunch instead and just enjoy the scenery and our accomplishment.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skylinesnowshoe/frozenlake.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>After a nice lunch, we turned around and headed down. The going down was much easier, minus the out-of-control sledders and frigid wind blasts.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skylinesnowshoe/alldone.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Everyone ended the day with a smile on their face, so I would have to say that it was a very nice trip.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2010 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/snowshoeing_at_skyline</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/skyline_lake_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Evolution of a Tree House - Part 3</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/evolution_of_a_treehouse_3</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/treehouse.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Wrapped up some work on the treehouse awhile ago, but never posted the pictures, so you here go:</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/treehouse/ladder.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Finally replaced the aluminum extension ladder with a real ladder - very sturdy and nice<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/treehouse/ladder.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Finally replaced the aluminum extension ladder with a real ladder - very sturdy and nice<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/treehouse/structure.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Up the ladder...<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/treehouse/railing.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>We made the railing out of some fallen trees from around our property<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/treehouse/sideview.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Here it is almost done<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/treehouse/fromafar.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>View from the yard<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>The treehouse is not quite done - still needs a handrail on the ladder and some window screens, but constructions is wrapped up for the winter.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2009 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/evolution_of_a_treehouse_3</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/treehouse_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Evolution of a Tree House - Part 2</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/evolution_of_a_treehouse_2</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/treehouse.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Framing:</p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/framing.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/framing2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/framing3.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/three_framed_walls.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/from_afar1.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Siding:</p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/inside.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/inside2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/inside3.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/looking_up.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/walls_done.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/from_afar.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Up next...the roof</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/evolution_of_a_treehouse_2</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/treehouse_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Evolution of a Tree House - Part 1</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/evolution_of_a_treehouse_1</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/treehouse.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Step 1 - You might think we should start with the tree, but I didnt take any pictures of the trees before I started, so lets skip ahead.</p>

<p>Step 2 - Build bracketry. Why use just wood when using metal means I get to weld something?</p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/brackets2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Step 3 - Integrate wood and metal</p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/brackets_bolted.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Step 4 - Attach supports to tree. The supports run up at a 45° angle to support the four main beams.</p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/support2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/support3.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/support.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><em>(i thought they turned out pretty nice, if i do say so myself)</em></p>

<p>Step 5 - Step back and get the big picture. Those are some tall trees</p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/tallness.jpg" width="480"></p>

<p>Step 6 - Repeat process on second tree. Here is a shot of one side complete and the second side going up</p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/3beams.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Step 7 - Install floor so you dont have to keep balancing on the small edge of the 2x6s.</p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/floor2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/floor.jpg" width="480"></p>

<p>Step 8 - Enjoy!</p></p>

<p><img src="/img/treehouse/eden.jpg" width="480"></p>

<p>But the evolution is not complete - we have the support structure and floor in place, but the treehouse is missing the 'house' part (a 'treefloor' just doesnt have the same ring to it). Check back later to see how it progresses.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2009 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/evolution_of_a_treehouse_1</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/treehouse_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mt. Rainier Summit Climb</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/climbing_mt_rainier</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/mtrainier.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>June 5th-8th I headed to Mt. Rainier to attempt a summit climb. Although it is a two day climb, it is really more like one really long day. On the first day, you hike about 4-5 miles from Paradise up to Camp Muir (@ 10,000 ft) and then that same night around midnight, you head out on the summit portion (another few miles and another 4,000 ft up).</p>

<p>The weather at Paradise when we left on Sunday morning was lousy, kind of misty and rainy and foggy, but at least it wasnt very cold.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtrainierclimb/foggy.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>We hiked about an hour at a time, and then took 10-15 minute breaks inbetween. Here is the rest of my team taking a break about halfway up. From this point on, we got above the cloud cover and it was super sunny and hot. A few smart guys were hiking in short and t-shirts and that turned out to be the best idea of all.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtrainierclimb/team_break.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Here are a couple of shots looking across and up the mountain. You can see the huge crevasses that are opening up as the summer wears on.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtrainierclimb/crevasse.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtrainierclimb/crevasse2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Only a few other peaks were tall enough to poke up above the cloud cover.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtrainierclimb/poking_up.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Is that where we are headed?</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtrainierclimb/upper.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>We arrived at Camp Muir around 4 in the afternoon and a lots of other teams and people were already there, hanging out and waiting for their summit attempts.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtrainierclimb/camp_muir.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>After a sleepless few hours, we all assembled around midnight to head out on the summit push. It was snowing lightly and I was actually excited to get going.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtrainierclimb/dark_start.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>I didnt get any more good pictures past Camp Muir because 1) most of the summit climb was in the dark, 2) once you are climbing, there is very little stopping and no chance to take pictures while you climb, 3) when we finally did reach the summit, my camera was frozen (along with our water, sunscreen, and pretty much everything else). One of the other climbers said that their dad had climbed the mountain about 30 years prior and had a celebratory Rainier beer at the summit, so they had packed a few bottles along as well and we enjoyed the world's coldest beer on top of the world.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mtrainierclimb/rainier_on_rainier.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The trek down was pretty exciting too since we finally got to see the crevasses and icefalls that we had been threading around in the dark on the way up. (Jumping over a two-foot wide bottomless crevasse seems somewhat more palatable when you cant see anything but the headlamp-illuminated snow directly in front of you). Highly recommended!</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/climbing_mt_rainier</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/mtrainier_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Hoh River Rafting</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/hoh_river_rafting</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/hoh.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Gianni has been in town so we decided to drag her along on an adventure. This time we headed to the Olympic peninsula for some vampire hunting and some river rafting.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/hohrafting/forks.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Is this where the vampires are?<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/hohrafting/bears.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>These bears were getting a little too friendly<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/hohrafting/ready.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Suited up and ready to go<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/hohrafting/blue.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Look at that water color<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/hohrafting/rivervalley.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Hoh River valley<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/hohrafting/rapids.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Those canoers ^^^ actually flipped in this rapid and nearly taco'ed their boat<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/hohrafting/eden.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/hohrafting/gianni.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/hohrafting/crew.jpg" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/hohrafting/smiles.jpg" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Big smiles all around<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/hoh_river_rafting</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/hoh_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Landscaping: Part Four</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/landscaping_4</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/grass.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Actually, this is parts 4 and 5 all rolled into one. When last we left the backyard, it was shaping up, but still had a long way to go.</p>

<p>The first project was to get the bark/mulch spread on the second large mound. Turns out we have <em>way</em> too much mulch left over, so we are trying to find places to use it up. One of the places we decided to use some was next to the deck, behind the garage. In order to transition from the bedding to the walkway and yard, michaleen had the idea to use some of our found rocks to build a boulder wall. It turned out great, including the little nooks for plants:</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/boulder_wall.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/little_gems.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>We finally got the deck stained (not without some incident, but that is another story), so it was time to spruce it up a bit. We got some really nice adirondack chairs from a guy here on Whidbey Island who makes them from local wood - they are really comfortable. We also got some plants planted in our planters, including a tiny japanese maple, some native grasses, and some fresh herbs.</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/chairs.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/planters.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>We also finally used up the last of the slate flagstone that has been sitting in the middle of the yard for a few months. We havent permanently laid the stones yet, but you can see the beginning of our circle patio:</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/circle_patio.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>With the mounds in and mulched, the walkways all laid out, the deck complete, and even some trees and plants going in, the last major thing to tackle was the grass. After waiting around for it to be delivered all stinking day, it finally arrived at around 5 pm. Still, it only took a few hours and we went from a giant dirt patch to a really nice lawn:</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/grass_spiral.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/grass.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>While I was gone to Mt. Rainier, Michaleen finished mulching the play area so now the bedding and grass (in the backyard at least) are complete.</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/grass_playarea.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2009 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/landscaping_4</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/grass_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kayaking at Lake Union</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/kayaking_lake_union</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/lake_union.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Michaleen, Eden, her friend Carson, and I headed to the mainland and did some kayaking on Lake Union. It was really fun kayaking with the skyscrapers and Space Needle in the background, and checking out all of the ships and floating houseboats was also really interesting. Eden and Carson also had a great time exploring at Gas Works park. Pretty great day!</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/lakeunion/tandem.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/lakeunion/eden.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/lakeunion/gasworks.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/lakeunion/skyline.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2009 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/kayaking_lake_union</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/lake_union_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Landscaping: Part Three</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/landscaping_3</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/1805Scenic.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>In case you missed the first two exciting installments, let's recap:</p>

<p>Part I: <a href="/tractor_work">Tractor Work</a>
Mowed some weeds, leveled some dirt, and just generally got an idea of what we were working with</p>

<p>Part II: <a href="/deck">The Deck</a>
It only took several months and was still only 90% complete. (but really, it is quite nice if I do say so myself)</p>

<p>So now we move on to the thrilling third installment in our 434-part series: Better Know a Landscape - the Fightin' Landscapers!</p>

<p>We had already started working on the lower area of the backyard and completed a couple of retaining walls around the play area. We went ahead and built a similar wall on the other side. We also cleared some brush and put some edging around the lower yard area.</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/play_area.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/bottom_wall.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/lower_area.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>We also spent some time working on the trails leading into the woods from the backyard. We built some steps down a particularly steep portion and use some of our patio stones to make a nice stepping stone pathway.</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/path_entrance.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/trail_steps_above.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/trail_steps.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Next up - the front yard. After getting kind of neglected while we worked hard on the back yard, we decided to (temporarily) turn our attention to the front yard. We needed a bunch of dirt to shape the backyard, and the front yard needed a big parking space dug out, so we figured we could get all the dirt we needed that way. We hired Scotty Dozy (that is not his real name, but that is what we called him) to do the job. He brought in a big excavator and a bulldozer and did most of the work in one day. With 4 truck loads of gravel to top it off, we finally had a nice smooth driveway.</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/parking_area.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/parking_area2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/driveway.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/front.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Tthat left us with the big pile of dirt that we needed for the back, so it was time to switch gears and focus on the backyard again. This time we brought back the mighty little track loader to do our bidding. Load after load of dirt was moved and shaped into some contouring mounds surrounding a large circular yard area. We packed and raked the mounds smooth, and then proceeded to start covering them with 'local hogged fuel', which is kind of like really big mulch.</p>

<p>Now it was time to move back to the deck and patio. We had to replace a few boards on the deck that we never did like (well, at least one of us was really concerned about them anyway). We also added some more stones to the patio/walkway to start wrapping it around to the side of the house. It is really turning out nice.</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/deck_patio.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/walkway.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Last year when we moved in, we planted a tree for Earth day, so in keeping with our new tradition, we headed to Bayview nursery to find another tree to plant this year. We ended up with two: a Japanese maple called Katsura and a zig-zaggy weeping birch.</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/katsura.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/weeping_birch.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>We also have a bunch of plants that we got from the native plant sale to plant still, but for now they are doing just fine in some pots on the side of the house. (Although we saw some more mature serviceberry trees at the nursery and I am excited to get those planted and growing).</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/native_plants.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>After all of that, we still have a medium sized dirt pile left to deal with (although it was about 4 or 5 times this size when we started):</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/dirt_pile.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>We have also been saving all of our big rocks that we come across - not sure what we are going to do with them yet, but we have a pile of them waiting nonetheless.</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/rock_pile.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>More hogged fuel is on the way this coming weekend so we can get the rest of the bedding areas covered, and then (maybe) we will be ready to get some sod and actually have a yard for summer.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2009 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/landscaping_3</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/1805Scenic_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Kayaking Saratoga Passage</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/kayaking_saratoga_passage</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/kayak_saratoga.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>After raving about how peaceful my [morning kayaking in Langley][Morning] was, I even convinced Michaleen to join me for a paddle. The water was flat as glass and the Cascade mountains were out in full force.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/kayak_saratoga1.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/kayak_saratoga2.jpg" class="largeimg" /></p>

<p>Look at that smile!</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2009 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/kayaking_saratoga_passage</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/kayak_saratoga_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Barlow Butte Snowshoe</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/barlow_butte_snowshoe</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/barlowbutte.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>I convinced Michaleen to go on an overnight snowshoe hike with me down near Mt. Hood. We decided to stay at the Barlow Butte hut, part of the <a href="http://www.cascadehuts.com/winter_routes.php">Cascade Huts</a> system. The hike was not super long, but it was supremely peaceful and enjoyable to be out in the snow-covered forest.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/barlowsnowshoe/starting_out.png" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Heading out<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/barlowsnowshoe/action_shot.png" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/barlowsnowshoe/michaleen_meadow.png" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Michaleen with a smile<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/barlowsnowshoe/bigfoot.png" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/barlowsnowshoe/gnome_home.png" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Winter wonderland<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/barlowsnowshoe/last_ridge.png" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>The last climb up to the hut<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/barlowsnowshoe/hut_distance.png" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/barlowsnowshoe/hut.png" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>The hut comes into view<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/barlowsnowshoe/hut_bunks.png" class="largeimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/barlowsnowshoe/hut_kitchen.png" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>The hut bunks and kitchen<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/barlowsnowshoe/mthood2.png" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>The view of Mt. Hood from the hut<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/barlowsnowshoe/leaving_hut.png" class="largeimg" />
<figcaption>Michaleen heading back out the next morning<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2009 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/barlow_butte_snowshoe</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/barlowbutte_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Happy Halloween</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/happy_halloween</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/jackolanterns2008.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p><img src="/img/other/halloween2008.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/happy_halloween</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/jackolanterns2008_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Deck</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/deck</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/deck.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>The back deck isnt quite finished, but it is close. Check out the transformation:</p>

<p>Footings poured</p>

<p><img src="/img/deck/footings.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Because the septic tank is close to the house, we had to frame around the openings so we could cut out some access covers</p>

<p><img src="/img/deck/septic.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Here is the lower portion with the decking in process</p>

<p><img src="/img/deck/lower.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Decking all finished on the lower portion</p>

<p><img src="/img/deck/lower_finished.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The upper portion is all framed in</p>

<p><img src="/img/deck/upper_framed.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The decking going down on the upper portion</p>

<p><img src="/img/deck/upper_decking.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>We have to finish the decking on the upper portion, and then tackle the steps and railings, but at least it is semi-functional at this point.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2008 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/deck</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/deck_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Tractor Work</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/tractor_work</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/tractor_work.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>A couple of weeks back, we decided to start our landscaping in earnest. The first step was to get the 7-foot tall weeds mowed down so we could see what we were dealing with. We rented a tractor from the local rental place to do the job quickly:</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/tractor_work1.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>(You can only see a bit of it sticking up, but there is also several thousand pounds of broken up concrete in the back of my truck that came from removing the back steps so we could build the deck).</p>

<p>After getting the tractor unstuck from the ditch, the mowing went pretty quickly. So quickly that we decided to do a little more 'tractoring'. I cleared the area across the ravine (including cutting down some trees that had fallen during previous windstorms).</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/tractor_work2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>In the backyard, I was able to scrape back the edges of the yard up to the edge of the ravine and it added quite a bit of room for the yard. In the farthest north corner, I was also able to clear quite a large area that had been previously overgrown with brush and thistles.</p>

<p><img src="/img/landscaping/tractor_work3.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Now that the areas are cleared, now it is time to have some one (professional) come in and level everything out so we can get started putting in the grass, plantings, walls, walkways, etc.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2008 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/tractor_work</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/tractor_work_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Whistler Trip</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/whistler_trip</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/whistler_bike.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>A couple of weeks ago, Michaleen was going to Wisconsin for a family get-together and Eden was down in Phoenix, so I had a week to kill. I decided to head up to Whistler to do some mountain biking. Since I was going to be there for almost a week, I wanted to try to get in some other activities as well. After dropping Michaleen off for the airport, I headed north to Canada.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/passport.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>After a little trouble getting across the border (apparently not having any hotel reservations or knowing anyone in Canada made me seem suspicious), it was a nice drive up through Vancouver and along the Sea-to-Sky highway. They are doing a ton of road construction to prepare for the 2010 Olympics, but it went smoothly and I didnt get held up at all.</p>

<p>I had a list of three or four potential campsites near Whistler, and the first one I decided to try was the Cal-Cheak Provincial Park. It was almost deserted and I practically had the whole place to myself. I pitched camp and took a short hike around the area to check things out. There was a river running along the edge of the campsite with a cool suspension bridge that was real close to the water.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/campsite.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>On Wednesday morning, I woke up early and had a breakfast of scrambled eggs, mushrooms, and jalapenos, all rolled up in a tortilla. I set out for Whistler, which was only about 10 kilometers away. Today I was going rafting, so I met up with the outfitters and we hopped on the old school bus for the drive to the put-in. We were rafting the Elaho river down to Squamish. Shortly after we put in, we came to a spot where we could do some cliff jumping. The water was super cold (about 40 degrees) and you could see the waterfalls coming off of the glacier, carrying the melted snow and dumping right into the river. But, it sounded like fun anyway, so I took the plunge.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/cliffjump.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>In what would become a common theme for this trip, I didnt get too many other photos because we were in the thick of the action most of the time. I did borrow one photo from the website of the place that was doing photography, and I got one picture of some of the scenery while we had a short lunch break.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/rafting1.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/riverscenery.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Although it wasnt the longest trip, it was fun and I really enjoyed seeing the area from the river's perspecitve. I headed back to my camp and had some beef filet grilled up on my Coleman stove.</p>

<p>Thursday morning I didnt get up quite so early, so my breakfast consisted of two granola bars instead. Today I was doing the ziplines with a company called ZipTrek. They have two 'courses', the Bear and the Eagle, so I decided to do them both.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/ziptrekgroup.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Here we are, in all of our tourist glory, getting all roped up</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/ziptrekgroupheadedout.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The ziplines are up on Whistler mountain and cross back and forth over Fitzsimmons creek. There is an intricate maze of wooden platforms and walkways that zigzag through the old-growth trees.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/ziptrekplatform.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/ziptrekplatforms.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>It was a really fun experience, and it was fun to see how different people reacted. Some people were definitely freaked out and one lady even asked if she could back out after we got up to the first big zip line (although she did end up sticking it out and finishing the course). There were lots of screams and death-grips on the harness, but I thought it was really fun and relaxing to whiz through the air.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/zipline3.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/zipline6.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>In between the two courses, I had lunch at the Garibaldi Lift Company, which sits right next to the lower portion of the bike park. It was fun to watch the bikers come down off the mountain and get pumped up for the biking I would be doing the next few days.</p>

<p>Originally I planned to do some alpine hiking on Friday, but the Whistler gondola was not opening up for the season until the next day. There were a lot of options since Whistler in the summer is like an outdoor-adventure mecca, but I really came to ride so I decided to get in an extra day. It was nice to be able to ride the lifts up and bomb all the way back down with barely a pedal stroke. I hadnt ridden my downhill bike in quite awhile, so it was fun to get back in the groove and get more comfortable on it again.</p>

<p>One of the neat things about Whistler is that there are bears everywhere, and they are totally indifferent to people. From the lift, I would see bears on almost every other ride up. Usually they were just eating some grass and minding their own business. On one run down, we came around the corner for a stop and there were two bear cubs about 20 feet off the trail, playing on a log and totally ignoring us.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/bears.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/bearsupclose.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>We never did see mama bear, but since we were sure she was not far away, we moved on and left the little bears to play.</p>

<p>Saturday and Sunday were filled with more biking. I had signed up for the Richie Schley Freeride Camp, so I got to ride with some professional mountain bikers including Schley and Wade Simmons. We practiced cornering and jumping and drops, but mostly just rode tons of trails - some of which I wouldnt have dreamed I would have ridden normally. It was an incredible experience - the weather was awesome, the trails were perfect, and it was the best riding I had ever done. Unfortunately, there was so much riding that it didnt leave any time for picture-taking. All I got was a shot of the lower bike park and the sign up at the start of A-Line (probably the signature trail at Whistler).</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/bikeparkview.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/whistler/alinesign.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Sunday night, I broke camp and headed home. This time the border crossing was a breeze - took about 15 seconds total. The trip was great and even with the rafting and ziplining and biking, I felt like there was so much more to do and i cant wait to go back!</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2008 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/whistler_trip</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/whistler_bike_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Climbing Mt. Hood</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/climbing_mt_hood</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/mthood.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Last weekend I went down to Oregon to climb Mt. Hood. Sunday night we started at 3am and got to ride the snowcat up to the top of the ski lift (since the lifts dont run at 3am in the morning). From there, we climbed from about 8,500ft up to the summit at just over 11,200ft. We summitted around 6:45am or so, too late too see the sunrise, but still got treated to some beautiful views. The weather was unseasonably warm (read: super hot), but the climb was fun and I had a great time. Not too many pictures since we only stopped a couple of times for quick breaks and only spent 5 or 10 minutes on top, but you can see the sunny weather and other cascade mountains (Adams, Rainier, and St. Helens to the north, Jefferson and Three Sisters to the south). All in all, a great day (minus the sunburnt lips and neck).</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mthood/gear2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mthood/me_glasses.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mthood/view_from_parking_lot2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mthood/snowcat.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mthood/dawn2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mthood/summit_ridge.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mthood/summit.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mthood/summit2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mthood/view_north.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mthood/view_northwest.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mthood/view_south.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mthood/way_down.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/mthood/way_down2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2008 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/climbing_mt_hood</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/mthood_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Trip to Canada, eh?</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/trip_to_canada_eh</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/seaplane.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Trip length: 3 days
Cities visited: 2 (Victoria, Vancouver)
Modes of transportation used: 7 (float plane, walking, bus, helicopter, train, seabus, ferry)</p>

<p><img src="/img/trips/canada2008/seaplane.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/trips/canada2008/space_needle.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/trips/canada2008/brian_and_michaleen.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/trips/canada2008/gasworks.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/trips/canada2008/craigdarroch_castle2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/trips/canada2008/lit_up_building.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/trips/canada2008/michaleen_boarding_helicopt.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/trips/canada2008/dedutch.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/trips/canada2008/tree_walk.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2008 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/trip_to_canada_eh</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/seaplane_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New House</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/new_house</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/1805Scenic.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Well, it is finally official - we bought a new house. We dont have to be out of this one until the end of may, so we are hoping to move a little at a time instead of everything all at once.</p>

<p><img src="/img/scenic/house2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2008 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/new_house</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/1805Scenic_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Skagit River Kayak</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/skagit_river_kayak</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/skagit_river.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>This past weekend I took a nice kayak trip down the lower <a href="http://www.fs.fed.us/r6/mbs/skagit-wsr/">Skagit River</a>. Between December and February, the middle portion of this trip is a very popular place to <a href="http://www.northcascades.com/images/eco-eagle-tree.jpg">view bald eagles</a>, but I was about a month late for that. The weather forecast was calling for snow showers all weekend, and on the drive to the put-in, it was a snowy, slushy mess. I was thinking this trip was off to a bad start, but as I got closer to the starting point, the weather cleared up a bit and things started looking up.</p>

<p>I started near the confulence of Copper Creek, about six miles or so above Marblemount. Here I am, ready to get going...</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skagitriver/me_start.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>...and my trusty Swifty is ready to go as well:</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skagitriver/kayak_gear.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The plan was to kayak about 16 miles or so to Rockport and camp overnight, then continue the next day another 16 miles or so to Rasar State Park. I had my tent and sleeping bag and a dry set of clothes all packed up in dry bags as I set out for my first ever overnight kayak trip.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skagitriver/putin.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Most of the whitewater on the Skagit is above where I put in, so I figured I would have a nice leisurely float ahead of me. For the most part, that was the case, but there were a few bigger riffles here and there to keep me on my toes, and even the flat sections were flowing very rapidly, so I didnt even have to paddle much and still sped down the river.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skagitriver/kayak_view_start.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skagitriver/kayak_view_start2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Although the snow had stopped, there was still quite a bit of snow in the area (although you cant really see it in these pictures). There was also a layer of fog up above the river, and the combination of the crystal clear river, crisp air, blanket of snow, and hanging fog made for a very peaceful and beautiful float.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skagitriver/foggy_trees.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skagitriver/fog.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Because the water was flowing so quickly, I made very quick time to my camp spot at Rockport. I beached the kayak and set up the tent, happy to find that everything I had packed had stayed nice and dry.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skagitriver/tent.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skagitriver/kayak_beached.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>As I fell asleep that night, I could hear the rain and ice falling outside. I wondered what the weather would hold for the second half of the trip, and the next morning, I found out. I awoke to a covering of slushy snow and snow still coming down.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skagitriver/snowy_tent.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skagitriver/snowy_kayak.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>I packed all of my gear and stuffed my soaking-wet tent into a plastic bag and set off. I had never kayaked in the falling snow before, and it was actually very peaceful. I had plenty of clothes on to keep me warm, and my gear was keeping my dry, so other than the occassional snowflake in the eye, it was nice to be out paddling in those conditions.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skagitriver/kayak_view_snow.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The river was still moving very quickly, and with the falling snow and glacier-cold water (the water temperature was hovering around 40 degrees), I was cautious to make sure I stayed up right and dry. Eventually, the snow stopped, followed by a short spell of rain, and then the sun came out. During the last 8 miles or so, the river widened just a bit and the flow slowed down slightly, making me have to paddle a bit more than before. I passed through some really pretty sections though and was content to keep my slow pace as I made my way down the river.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/skagitriver/kayak_view_mossyrocks.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The last mile or so, the wind came up a bit and slowed my progress a little more. My take-out spot (Rasar State Park) did not have an actual boat launch, just some sandy beaches a few hundred yards from the actual park. That would make spotting the take-out from the river a little tricky, but yesterday before I started out, I had stopped at the park and walked down to the beach to try to get an idea of what the area looked like and committed it to memory. As I floated farther down the river, I kept a watchful eye out for anything that looked familiar, but from the view from my kayak, quite a bit of the shoreline looked the same. I finally saw some sandy beaches that looked extra familiar and made the correct guess that I had reached my destination. After having to carry my kayak and gear about 200 yards up to the park, my trip was complete. Even though I was late in the season, I had seen about 5 or 6 eagles, tons of ducks and geese, and even a solitary beaver hanging out on the shore as I floated by.</p>

<p>Thanks a ton to Michaleen and crew for driving way out of their way to shuttle my truck for me. All in all, it was a very memorable trip and an area that I would like to explore some more.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/skagit_river_kayak</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/skagit_river_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Christmas Ornaments</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/christmas_ornaments</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/ornaments.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Spent some time last week making christmas ornaments for the tree. Pretty amazing what you can make out of some glitter and beads.</p>

<p><img src="/img/other/ornaments1.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/other/ornaments2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/other/ornaments3.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/other/xmastree1.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/other/xmastree2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2007 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/christmas_ornaments</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/ornaments_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Potato Chips</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/potato_chips</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/potato_chips.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>We have been getting pretty crafty in the kitchen lately and made some really good food. This time however, we decided to try something a little more fun: homemade potato chips</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/food/chips1.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>The whole operation<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/food/chips2.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Cooking away<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/food/chips3.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Looking pretty tasty<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/food/chips4.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>The final product<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>We also made some baked sweet potato chips (no pictures) and I would say that all in all, they turned out really good.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2007 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/potato_chips</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/potato_chips_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Thanksgiving</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/thanksgiving</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/thanksgiving.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Just a nice shot of our Thanksgiving spread</p>

<p><img src="/img/food/thanksgiving07.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2007 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/thanksgiving</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/thanksgiving_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Pumpkin Carving</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/pumpkin_carving</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/jackolanterns.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Here are some pictures from this past weekend's pumpkin carving session:</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/other/pumpkins0.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Pre-carving set up (notice the dremel for those advanced pumpkin carvers)<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/other/pumpkins_eden.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Eden's masterpiece<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/other/pumpkins_rachelle.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Rachelle (Eden's friend)<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/other/pumpkins_michaleen.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Michaleen<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/other/pumpkins_brian.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Brian<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/other/pumpkins1.jpg" class="smallimg" />
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/other/jackolanterns.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Whole scary lot of them<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/pumpkin_carving</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/jackolanterns_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New Kayak and Rack</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/kayak_and_rack</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/kayak_langley.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>A few months ago, I got a new sea kayak but never put up a picture of it. I havent gotten to use it nearly as much I would have liked since I didnt have an easy way to transport it (at 17' long, I couldnt just throw it in the bed of my truck like I can with my swifty). But I finally got a good rack setup so I can haul the thing around.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/rack.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2007 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/kayak_and_rack</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/kayak_langley_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Camping @ Cooper Lake</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/camping_at_cooper_lake</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/cooper_lake.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>A couple of weekends ago we went camping at Cooper Lake, north of Cle Elum. We had originally planned to go to Wind River, but we didnt want to spend the whole weekend driving, so we found an alternate site that was a little closer to home. We tried to do some fishing, but didnt catch anything. The area was beautiful though, and we were able to kayak and read and just generally relax.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/cooperlake/camp.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/cooperlake/eden_kayak.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/cooperlake/michaleen_kayak.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Aug 2007 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/camping_at_cooper_lake</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/cooper_lake_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Otter Falls</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/otter_falls</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/otter_falls.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>This past weekend, Michaleen, Eden, and I decided to do a hike up to Otter Falls (actually the <a href="http://www.fs.fed.us/r6/mbs/recreation/activities/trails/snrd/snrd_1002.htm">Snoqualmie Lake Trail #1002</a>). It was only about an hour drive to the Taylor River trailhead, and as predicted, it was raining. However, the rain was light so we decided it wasnt going to stop us.</p>

<p>The trail isnt very steep, but it involves a lot of stream crossings and, with all of the rain, some really muddy sections. Eden quickly found a trusty (or so we thought) stick and some higher ground.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/otterfalls/eden_and_stick.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>At about two miles in, we came to the Marten Creek bridge. The Marten Creek Falls were amazingly pretty. The rocks, the trees, the sound of the rushing water - it was all very picturesque.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/otterfalls/marten_creek.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/otterfalls/marten_creek_downstream.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/otterfalls/eden_marten_creek.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/otterfalls/michaleen_and_eden_marten_creek.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The rain was sort of off and on on the hike up. It hinted at raining harder a few times, but for the most part, it was just a constant drizzle. But the trail was so beautiful that the wet weather wasnt dampening anyone's fun.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/otterfalls/michaleen_and_eden.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/otterfalls/michaleen_and_eden_closeup.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Along with the numerous stream crossings, we also passed several smaller waterfalls and lots of other cool things, like moss-covered trees that looked like gnarled green monsters. Here were some mushrooms that Eden found, as well as a tall tree that looked neat.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/otterfalls/mushrooms2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/otterfalls/tall_tree.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>We forged on, crossing a few more streams before arriving at the cairns that marked the trail up to Otter Falls.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/otterfalls/michaleen_crossing.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The falls were awesome and well worth the hike. I had been here once before (15 years ago), and it was just as pretty as I remembered. We had packed a picnic lunch, so we spread out our blanket and sat down to enjoy the food and the view.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/otterfalls/falls2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/otterfalls/picnic.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The rain was picking up, as was the wind, so we ended up moving our picnic to a more sheltered spot. By this point, everyone was very wet and getting cold, so we cut our picnic short and headed back. The first two miles or so of the hike back were pretty good, but the rain was definitely starting to come down harder. By the time we got back to the Marten Creek bridge, it was a downpour. The trail turned into a constant stream of mud. I have to give everyone credit though - there was no complaining or sour moods. We put our heads down and made good time, all the while focusing on getting back to the dryness and warmth of the truck. We finally arrived back at the truck, soaked and cold, but in the end, everyone had a good time.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2007 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/otter_falls</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/otter_falls_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lunchtime Visitor</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/lunchtime_visitor</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/deer.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Michaleen and Eden were in the kitchen and I had just came in from the garage (<a href="http://fj40.blogspot.com">working on the landcruiser</a>), and look who came walking up our trail...</p>

<p><img src="/img/other/deer3.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/other/deer2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2007 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/lunchtime_visitor</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/deer_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Double Bluff</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/double_bluff</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/double_bluff.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>While looking for some good hikes on the island, I came across Double Bluff. It was supposed to have a few miles of forested trails, but it turned out to be a cool place to hike along the beach instead. My first visit was kind of rushed since I was trying to hurry back, but Michaleen and Eden and I have made a couple of return trips to collect shells and play in the (very cold) water. It is fun to watch the clams squirting water up into the air like some kind of big erratic fountain and to see the (literally) millions of shells from clams, mussels, oysters, snails, crabs, barnacles, and all kinds of other interesting sea life. On the last trip, we also saw three big cruise ships go by, possibly on their way to Alaska. Those things are gigantic! Maybe next time I will get a picture.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/double_bluff.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/double_bluff_ocean.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2007 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/double_bluff</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/double_bluff_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Morning Kayak</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/morning_kayak</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/kayak_langley.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Today was my second time out for a morning kayak on Puget Sound (in the Saratoga Passage, to be exact). Last weekend was the Langley 'Welcome the Whales' festival, so I have been really hoping to see a whale during my kayaking. Today I didnt see a whale, but I did see a huge sea lion who was about 25 feet from my kayak in the middle of the sound. I thought it was just a big piece of driftwood at first, until I got closer and heard him breathing and blowing water out of its nose. He didnt seem to mind my presence too much, and after a little while, he dove his head under, flipped up his tail, and was gone. I wasnt able to grab a picture of him, but here are some pictures of the sound in the morning - very peaceful.</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/kayak_boats.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Boats moored near Langley<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/kayak_sound2.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Puget Sound<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><img src="/img/outdoors/kayak_langley2.jpg" class="smallimg" />
<figcaption>Seaside Village of Langley<figcaption>
</figure>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2007 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/morning_kayak</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/kayak_langley_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mountain Biking at Goss Lake Woods</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/goss_lake_woods</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_ferngully.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Having moved up here to Whidbey Island, it had been several months since I had ridden my bike and I had yet to get out and explore what the area had to offer. For christmas, I had received <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Kissing-Trail-Greater-Mountain-Adventures/dp/1881583090/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1/104-0840380-3377562?ie=UTF8&amp;s=books&amp;qid=1174521156&amp;sr=8-1">Kissing the Trail</a>, a mountain biking book containing 'Greater Seattle Mountain Bike Adventures'. I was anxious to get out for a local ride, so I turned to the section on Whidbey Island to see what I could find. Although there were only two local rides listed, the trails at <a href="http://gosslakewoods.org">Goss Lake Woods</a> were described as narrow and twisty, with <strong>minimal elevation gain</strong> - how could I pass that up? (By the way, that was their emphasis, not mine) =). After a short drive to the trailhead, I pedaled out into the slightly damp forest along a picturesque trail.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/glw_trailhead.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The ride started out on the easy-sounding Frog Lane, Two Kitties, and Jane Erye trails. The trails were wide and smooth, but there were enough fun rollercoasters to put a smile on my face and get my heart pumping. I turned north and looped along the west side of the trust lands, already feeling the effects of not riding in so long. The trails were still pretty tame, but the damp air and lush forest created a quiet stillness that was fun just to enjoy. Plus, the guide book had promised that I was close to Blazing Saddles a 'very technical trail' with 'lots of ups and downs and tight turns in and out of the wrinkles of the forest floor'. So i pedalled onward, enjoying the fresh air and serene surroundings.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/glw_fallen.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>After a couple of deadends and one or two steep hills (hey! I thought there were no hills out here!), I ended up over on the east side of the preserve, up on top of a hill that opened into a grassy meadow surrounded by tall pine trees. It was a little windy in the open meadow, and it felt as if I could have just as easily been on a windswept hillside in a remote part of New Zealand. I hadnt found the technical trails that I was looking for, but the ride was turning out to be really good just the same. I did one more short loop and then started to head back to the trailhead. On the ride back, i noticed a tiny trail heading off to the right into a thick stand of trees. I turned onto the trail and almost immediately found myself surrounded by the dark forest and moss-covered trees. The trail looked like it wasnt used nearly as much as the others, and the fallen trees and roots made for a fun and challenging ride.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/glw_logs.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>The trail linked me up with another network of trails that turned out to be exactly what I was after. The trails of Flying Squirrel, Sleepy Hollow, and Stryx Varia were incredible - twisty and narrow, zigzagging over roots and squeezing between the towering trees with just enough ups and downs to keep the momentum up and my tires rolling quickly. I felt like I was in my own personal mountain biking heaven (not to mention that I didnt see another person or track on the entire ride).</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/glw_flyingsquirrel.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/glw_ladder.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>I ended up on some truly single track (about 6" wide, with forest vegetation obscuring the trail in most places) before finally cruising back on the lazily named Lulu Lane. I arrived back at my truck with mud in my teeth and a grin on my face - exactly what I had been looking forward to.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2007 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/goss_lake_woods</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_ferngully_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Winter on Whidbey</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/winter_on_whidbey</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/snowtree.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>We just left Arizona a few weeks ago, but have gotten settled in and already enjoying the winter here on Whidbey. Even got enough snow to build a snowman - wouldnt have been able to do that in Phoenix. ⛄</p>

<p><img src="/img/other/winter_walkway.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/other/snowman.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/other/snowtree.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2007 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/winter_on_whidbey</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/snowtree_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Waking Up On Whidbey</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/waking_up_on_whidbey</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/ferry.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Well, we have arrived on Whidbey Island. It was three days of driving nearly 1600 miles. It started off poorly when the Uhaul truck had brake problems before we even left the lot. And then more problems again before we left Phoenix (supposedly loose wiring in the dash). And the radio didnt work, and neither did the windshield wipers (luckily we had good weather for the whole trip, even through Portland and Seattle). When we pulled up to the new house, there were two service trucks in the driveway because the gas furnace was not working. It was a toasty 42 degrees in the house when we arrived. But, they got the heat fixed and the truck did make it without leaving us stranded. And although I was sure we wouldnt be so lucky, all of our stuff survived the trip mostly unscathed. We still have stacks of boxes to go through and unpack, but we are making progress. We have already tried the local Chinese place and the local pizza place (twice). I guess we are no longer Arizonans and officially Washingtonians.</p>

<p><img src="/img/other/uhaul.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/waking_up_on_whidbey</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/ferry_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Old House Sold - New House Rented</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/moving_to_whidbey</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_ferngully.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Well, my house finally sold. It was a quick and easy closing, so that part was nice. The worst part was moving out - not the house (since i dont have hardly any possessions), but the garage, since it was filled with hundreds of landcruiser parts of all shapes and sizes. I actually missed out on all of the fun of the move since I was out of the state at the time, but Michaleen and her girls saved the day by handling it all for me. I owe them big time.</p>

<p>Anyway, now that I am out of my old house, it was time to turn the attention to finding a new place up on Whidbey Island. Since we arent sure what our long-term plan is, we decided that renting a place for now was the best idea. We found a great place that is on 5 treed acres on top of a hill, with great views of the Puget Sound, mainland, and Cascade mountains. You can see the view in a couple of these pictures.</p>

<p><img src="/img/other/view.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/other/view2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>This last picture is of the house we are renting. We have only seen the outside and peeked in a few windows, so we dont even know what the inside looks like yet. Guess it will be fun to find out when we arrive up there next month.</p>

<p><img src="/img/other/view3.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/moving_to_whidbey</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bd_ferngully_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Flagstaff Adventure Race III</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/flagstaff_ar_3</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/flagstaff_ar.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>It was a beautiful day to race up in flagstaff - the weather was great, the leaves were changing colors, and Mark put together a fun race for the series finale. Team Sierra Adventure Sports was hoping to do well following their 1st place division finish at the last race. Alas, it was not our day and we finished 3rd (out of only three teams in our division) and only a couple places up from being last overall.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/far_finish2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>However, since we did well in the previous two races of the season, our 3rd place finish was enough to keep us in the lead in the points series, so I am happy to announce that Team Sierra Adventure Sports takes 1st place in the 3-person division for the 1st annual Flagstaff Mountain Racing Series. We even got a little trohpy and some cool prizes for our achievement. As Rick said later, "we raced against Monster, and we were the ones who came home with the trophy" (even if that statement is slightly misleading).</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/flagstaff_ar_3</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/flagstaff_ar_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Desert Rage - San Diego</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/desert_rage_san_diego</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/lake_hodges.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>This past weekend was Desert Rage - San Diego, the third race in the Desert Rage series and the first one I had done outside of Arizona. The event took place on Lake Hodges, and although i had high hopes of spotting <a href="http://www.hodgee.com/">Hodgee</a>, he was nowhere to be seen that day.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.hodgee.com/photo1.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>As for the race, it was 11+ miles of kayaking, about 9 miles of trekking, and 13-ish miles of mountain biking for a grand total of almost 34 miles. I finished 4th in the solo division, which wasnt all that great of a finish, but I was still pretty happy with the outcome.</p>

<p>You can check out the full results and a bunch of pictures on the <a href="http://www.sierraadventuresports.com/sierrahome2results.htm">Sierra Adventure Sports website</a>.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/desert_rage_san_diego</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/lake_hodges_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Gilmore Adventure Race 2006</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/gilmore_ar</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/gilmore_ar.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Team Sierra Adventure Sports takes 2nd in the male 3-person category at the 2006 Gilmore Adventure Race! It was a long hard course, but everyone had a great time. <a href="http://www.zdap.com/racereports/viewtopic.php?t=6877">Read Rick's full write-up at Adventure Race Reports</a>.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/gilmore.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/gilmore_ar</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/gilmore_ar_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Home Updates</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/2046_dayton</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/2046_dayton.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>The home improvement projects are finally wrapping up and the end is in sight. Spent most of Monday wrapping up the exterior landscaping and, with a lot of help from Michaleen, things look great! My house has never looked so good (if i do say so myself).</p>

<p>
<figure><p><img src="/img/house/house1.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><p><img src="/img/house/house2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><p><img src="/img/house/house.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><p><img src="/img/house/picture8.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>
</figure>
</p>

<p>
<figure><p><img src="/img/house/picture10.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>
</figure>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/2046_dayton</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/2046_dayton_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Flagstaff Adventure Race II</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/flagstaff_ar_2</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/flagstaff_ar.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Last saturday was the second race of the first annual Mountain Racing Sports Flagstaff Adventure Racing 3-race Series. Team Sierra Adventure Sports had finished 1st in the 3-person division (6th overall) in the first race on May 20th and was looking to do well again in the second race of the year. We ended up with an additional racer for this race, making us the only 3-person team with 4 people. We gained time with some strategic puzzle-picking and Rick's usual spot-on navigation. We also made up some ground on the bike leg, barely edgeing out in front of the guys from Gilmore Adventure Racing. At a blind-folded rock-climbing mystery event, we put some more distance between us (it helped that Carter just happens to own his own rock climbing wall). In the final ride-n-tie section, we knew that team Gilmore Adventure Racing was right behind us and closing the gap.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/far_close_behind.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>We were all beat, but determined to stay out in front. In the end, it was a sprint to the finish, but we edged them out by a mere 7 seconds! It was good enough for a 2nd place finish in our division, 5th overall.</p>

<p><img src="/img/outdoors/far_finish.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p>Check out some race photos at <a href="http://www.sierraadventuresports.com/sierrahome2gallery.htm">http://www.sierraadventuresports.com/sierrahome2gallery.htm</a> and see the official results at <a href="http://www.mtnracingsports.com/results.htm">http://www.mtnracingsports.com/results.htm</a></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/flagstaff_ar_2</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/flagstaff_ar_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stop-motion Studies - Unfinished Masterpiece</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/lego_unfinished_masterpiece</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_talking.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>I may never finish my Lego stop-motion film, so I am going to share it with the world as-is. This was my first attempt at a proper film, and I learned a lot about the process while making it. It is not very long (and has almost no plot), but it took a surprising amount of work just to get this far.</p>

<p>Anyway, enjoy it in all of its unfinished glory:</p>

<p>
<iframe width="740" height="416" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q01Dbve4Y_U?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/lego_unfinished_masterpiece</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_talking_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Cellar Door - Finally Done</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/cellar_door</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/2046_dayton.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>I dont know how many of you were lucky enough to get to see the 'interesting' cellar door that was in the house when I first moved in. For those that werent so lucky, imagine a giant trap door in the middle of my dining room, that was first tiled over, and then re-cut out so it could still open. Between scratching up the wall, weighing about 100 pounds, and just being incovenient, I knew it had to go. I ripped it out and then was left with the dilemna of how to construct something better. I figured out a ladder-type access that would take up less than half the space, and not interfere with anything else in the room. I did the initial construction a while back, but never got around to finishing it. Well, it is finally done! I was a little worried about what it would end up looking like, but I think it turned out pretty nice. Here are a couple of pictures so you dont have to use your imagination.</p>

<p><img src="/img/house/cellar_door.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/house/cellar_door_open.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/cellar_door</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/2046_dayton_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New Carpet</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/new_carpet</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/new_carpet.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Spent last week ripping out the old carpet in my bedroom and office, painting the walls, and getting new carpet installed. Turned out pretty good I think.</p>

<p><img src="/img/house/carpet_bedroom.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/house/carpet_office.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/new_carpet</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/new_carpet_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>BrickFest Montage Clip 2 - Psycho</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/lego_psycho</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_psycho.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Here is my second attempt at a montage clip for the <a href="http://www.brickfest.com">Brickfest</a> montage. It is not technically perfect, but I had a lot of fun making it, and hopefully it is recognizable even though the movie is over 40 years old.</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Nls1pmXWtr4?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

<p>Here are some of the things that I wished I had improved upon:</p>

<ul>
<li>Animation ended up a little herky-jerky because I had to slow it down a bit to match up with the audio</li>
<li>The zoom/pan was much faster than in the real movie, but again I had to match up my animation with the audio</li>
<li>The set was so tight that I had to use some extra legos to move the knife-wielder, and then forgot to mask them out, so they are visible in a few shots</li>
<li>The lighting is very close to the original, but not exact. The knife-wielder should have been more shadowy</li>
<li>The 'scream' mouth. I didnt have any appropriate minifig heads, so I had to draw the mouth in Photoshop. Not my best work, but better than the version I originally did</li>
<li>I was generally happy with the water effect for the shower, although it is not quite as obvious after the compression</li>
</ul>

<p>Anyway, let me know what you think.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/lego_psycho</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_psycho_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Big Sky Breakdown - Cancelled</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/big_sky_breakdown_cancelled</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bigskybreakdown.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>On the eve of our big training trip up in the White Mountains, Brad found out at the last minute that the Big Sky Breakdown in Montana had been cancelled. Their website still says 'Registration is now open', and apparently Brad was the first person to hear the news. The organizers said that they had already had a fair amount of teams commit to doing it, but they had started planning too late and the course was still up in the air. They didnt want to put on their first race without it being top notch.</p>

<p>Anyway, it is a bummer to not be doing it. But maybe something else will pop up.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/big_sky_breakdown_cancelled</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bigskybreakdown_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stop-motion Study 4 - Mouth Animation</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/lego_study_4</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_talking.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Although I have not yet finished my first film, I have still been experimenting with different animation techniques. For this test, I wanted to play with animating the Lego figure's face to give more expression and the illusion of actually speaking. A great example of this technique is the Rapunzel short by Jay Silver - notice how the facial expressions really convey the minifig's emotions:</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Uyc6uLcbc-Y?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

<p>Anyway, I was feeling a little lazy and didnt want to shoot an entire scene just for this test, so I decided to use some existing footage from my upcoming film. I used the corresponding dialog from the scene as well (so this is a little sneak-peak at the final film, although the final cut will NOT use the actual mouth animations).</p>

<p>Next up, I downloaded a nifty program called Papagayo (<a href="http://www.lostmarble.com/papagayo/index.shtml">http://www.lostmarble.com/papagayo/index.shtml</a>) that is essentially a lip-synching program that lets you line up 'phonemes' (mouth shapes) with your sound. You type in your dialog, and it shows you the corresponding mouth shapes. Turns out there are only a handful of different shapes required for most sounds in the english language (long O, L, B, U, etc). You can also add your sound files and adjust the timing. Once you have all of of the timing figured out, it is just a matter of editing the frames.</p>

<p>So I opened up Photoshop and created my 5 necessary mouth shapes. This was not too hard, since I took a copy of the original Lego mouth and just edited it to the different shapes. Then, using the timing specified by Papagayo, I had to hand-edit the appropriate frames with the new mouth shapes. Save everything and render.</p>

<p>Here is the final result:</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/fSMvodIXgKA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

<p>Lessons learned:</p>

<ul>
<li>Adding mouth animations can make a big difference, especially on close-ups that would otherwise have little or no other animation to give the impression of speaking (moving hands/arms, etc)</li>
<li>Getting the timing correct is important. My clip ended up being slightly out of sync because I didnt spend too much time getting it right in Papagayo. The brain easily picks up on it when the mouth is not matching the sound</li>
<li>People dont convey all of their meaning with just their words. Adding in facial expressions (moving eyebrows, squinting eyes, etc) would make the illusion much more realistic. I will save that one for another study</li>
</ul>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/lego_study_4</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_talking_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>BrickFest Montage Clip - Blair Witch</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/lego_blair_witch</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_blair_witch.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Every year there is this big convention type thing related to Legos that is called Brickfest (<a href="http://www.brickfest.com">http://www.brickfest.com</a>). As part of Brickfest, Brickfilms usually sponsors an animation contest that goes along with the theme of Brickfest. Many animators participate, and some of the best lego movies of the year come from competitions like this.</p>

<p>This year at Brickfest, they decided to add another component as well. Before the public viewing of the animation competition entries, the organizers wanted to show a 3 minute montage of clips from famous movies, all re-created in Lego. The rules were simple: pick a famous scene from a famous movie, use the original audio track, animate the whole thing with Legos, and make it all less than about 30 seconds long. It sounded pretty fun, so I decided to try my hand at it. Here is my re-creation of The Blair Witch Project.</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3_P6c5HiOUA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/lego_blair_witch</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_blair_witch_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Big Sky Breakdown</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/big_sky_breakdown</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/bigskybreakdown.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>So, I have done more than 10 adventure races over the past three years, including 4 just this year so far. But all of these have been of the 'sprint' type, which does not mean you have to sprint during them, but they are fairly short, taking 3 to 8 hours to cover 15 to 30 miles. The most recent Desert Rage at Roosevelt Lake was a little longer, taking me nearly 12 full hours to complete, but still considered a sprint. I have thought about doing a couple 24-hour events, but so far everything has fell through.</p>

<p>But what got me (and probably most people) interested in adventure racing in the first place was the Eco-Challenge. This expedition-type race was much more than a few hours out in the desert. Teams had to cover literally hundreds of miles over all kinds of terrain, day and night. Strategy and determination became exponentially more important than just being 'fast'.</p>

<p>But most mortal people will never race in the Eco-Challenge. So what is a budding adventure racer to do? Enter the Big Sky Breakdown (<a href="http://www.bigskybreakdown.com">www.bigskybreakdown.com</a>) - an expedition-type race in Montana. The course promises to take racers on a 250-mile course that should take 3 to 4 days to complete. A couple of friends that I met through adventure racing (Brad and Yvonee of teams Tubac, Start Slow and Taper, and Plan B) have been doing Rogaine's and other 24-hour events and got the idea that they were ready to step up to something bigger. When they asked me if I would be interested, I jumped at the chance. Having raced with them several times before, I knew that they shared my outlook on things, namely:</p>

<ul>
<li>stay friends</li>
<li>have</li>
<li>finish the race</li>
<li>worry about going fast</li>
</ul>

<p>... in that order.</p>

<p>The race is at the end of July (27-30), so we only have two months to get all of our gear in order and prepare physically for the event. The race directors have already said that the events will include:</p>

<ul>
<li>trekking (hiking)</li>
<li>mountain biking</li>
<li>river kayaking</li>
<li>tough orienteering/navigation</li>
<li>rappelling and Tyrolean traverse</li>
</ul>

<p>The site goes into more detail about each event, and they also have a blog where they give peeks into the course and other aspects of the race. Take a look at their site and see if it is something you would consider doing.</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/big_sky_breakdown</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/bigskybreakdown_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Dam to Dam Kayak Race</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/dam_to_dam</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/tempetownlake.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Paddled in the Tempe Town Lake Dam-To-Dam kayak race yesterday (<a href="http://www.damtodamevents.com/index.html">http://www.damtodamevents.com/index.html</a>). This was the second year of the event, and my second time participating in it. Last year I did it solo in the recreational division. This year, I talked michaleen into doing it with me and we competed in the tandem kayak class. Thanks to Rick Eastman for letting us borrow his two-man kayak for the event. We even came home with a first place finish (nevermind the fact that we were the only entry in our division) =)</p>

<p><img src="/img/other/damtodam.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/dam_to_dam</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/tempetownlake_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Desert Rage II - Roosevelt Lake</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/desert_rage_2</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/lakeroosevelt.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>The Desert Rage II adventure race was yesterday at Roosevelt Lake. Rick promised that the race would be really tough, and he didnt disappoint. After the 4am dark start, we had a tough climb on the bike, followed by a crazy bike/hike down an old stream bed that is part of the Arizona Trail. Most of the 'trail' was either big boulders in the streambed, or overgrown brush on either bank. After the bushwack, there were several miles of killer climbs up some rocky powerline roads. Every team had to hike some of these sections. Then there was a superfast descent back down to the road and then back to the TA. Next up was a 9 mile paddle on Roosevelt Lake. With the new format of the final orienteering/trekking section, even the fastest teams were out right up until the cut-off time. I raced as a solo and finished with a time of 11 hours 25 minutes - good enough for a first place in the solo division =)</p>

<p>The race report and full results are posted on the Sierra Adventure Sports website: <a href="http://www.sierraadventuresports.com/sierrahome2results.htm">http://www.sierraadventuresports.com/sierrahome2results.htm</a></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/desert_rage_2</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/lakeroosevelt_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Mountain Biking at South Mountain</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/south_mountain</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/southmountain.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Too nice of a day to sit inside, so I headed to south mountain for a ride. Being <em>way</em> out of shape, the ride (hike) up National was long and hard. But it was all worth it for the awesome descent down.</p>

<p><img src="/img/other/biking4.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/other/biking5.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/other/cactusflower.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/south_mountain</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/southmountain_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Lego Film Project Update</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/lego_film_update_1</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_helicopter.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Right before I left for my bike trip, I talked with Josh and decided to do a film based sort of on the show '24' (his countdown timer was the inspiration).</p>

<p>Well, I started off with a lot of enthusiam, but the process is a bit tedious. I tried to write the whole script, but found I worked much better when I just sort of winged it. I finally got the first scene filmed after shooting it about 10 times (kept having lighting trouble and flicker). Once I got the lighting issues worked out, I was pretty happy with it. I shot the second scene in one take, so that helped the progress quite a bit.</p>

<p>At that point, I was out of storyline again. Although originally supposed to be based on 24, the movie is really now more of just a crime-fighting spoof (half Hong Kong Fooey, half Police Squad). I decided to work on the soundtrack while I thought more about the rest of the story. I put a lot of work into the soundtrack, and I am pretty happy with it so far. I had to go back and re-do some of the early stuff because the later stuff was much better and made the early stuff sound crappy.</p>

<p>I merged the soundtrack with the scenes so far (and wrote a nifty program to help preview and adjust timing as well), and it is turning out pretty good. Nothing earth-shattering, but I am happy with it. I hope to shoot a few more scenes in the near future, and maybe even wrap it up by the end of the month...</p>

<p><strong>[UPDATE]:</strong> After another (slightly shorter) hiatus, production has started up again. After a doing a couple of test takes of the next scene a couple of weeks ago, I finally got around to filming the final version. Filming went OK, although I had to shoot the entire scene three times before I was happy with it. I still had a noticable light change halfway through the scene, but it was nothing a little post-processing in Photoshop couldnt cure. Anyway, here is a teaser frame from the latest scene.</p>

<p><img src="/img/lego/clip.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2006 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/lego_film_update_1</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_helicopter_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Great Divide Mountain Bike Ride</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/great_divide_ride</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/greatdivideride.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>I just got back from a short bike ride - a ride that started two months ago and took me from the Canadian border all the way to Mexico. You can read more about my motivation and see dispatches from my trip at <a href="http://greatdivideride.blogspot.com">http://greatdivideride.blogspot.com</a></p>

<hr/>

<p><style>
    .ride .header {font-size:250%;}
    .ride .block {margin-top:20px;border-bottom:solid black 1px;}
    .ride .day {font-size:110%;font-weight:bold;}
    .ride .stats {font-size:105%;font-weight:normal;font-style:italic;margin-bottom:8px;}
    .ride .desc {margin-bottom:10px;}
    .ride .caption {width:640px;margin-bottom:15px;text-align:center;font-size:95%;font-weight:normal;font-style:italic;}
    .ride img {border:solid black 1px;margin-left:10px;}
</style></p>

<div class="ride">
        <div align="center">
        <a href="#day1">day 1</a> - <a href="#day2">day 2</a> - <a href="#day3">day 3</a> - <a href="#day4">day 4</a> - <a href="#day5">day 5</a> - <a href="#day6">day 6</a> - <a href="#day7">day 7</a> - <a href="#day8">day 8</a> - <a href="#day9">day 9</a> - <a href="#day10">day 10</a><br>
        <a href="#day11">day 11</a> - <a href="#day12">day 12</a> - <a href="#day13">day 13</a> - <a href="#day14">day 14</a> - <a href="#day15">day 15</a> - <a href="#day16">day 16</a> - <a href="#day17">day 17</a> - <a href="#day18">day 18</a> - <a href="#day19">day 19</a> - <a href="#day20">day 20</a><br>
        <a href="#day21">day 21</a> - <a href="#day22">day 22</a> - <a href="#day23">day 23</a> - <a href="#day24">day 24</a> - <a href="#day25">day 25</a> - <a href="#day26">day 26</a> - <a href="#day27">day 27</a> - <a href="#day28">day 28</a> - <a href="#day29">day 29</a> - <a href="#day30">day 30</a><br>
        <a href="#day31">day 31</a> - <a href="#day32">day 32</a> - <a href="#day33">day 33</a> - <a href="#day34">day 34</a> - <a href="#day35">day 35</a> - <a href="#day36">day 36</a> - <a href="#day37">day 37</a> - <a href="#day38">day 38</a> - <a href="#day39">day 39</a> - <a href="#day40">day 40</a><br>
        <a href="#day41">day 41</a> - <a href="#day42">day 42</a> - <a href="#day43">day 43</a> - <a href="#day44">day 44</a> - <a href="#day45">day 45</a> - <a href="#day46">day 46</a> - <a href="#day47">day 47</a> - <a href="#day48">day 48</a> - <a href="#day49">day 49</a> - <a href="#day50">day 50</a><br>
        <a href="#day51">day 51</a> - <a href="#day52">day 52</a> - <a href="#day53">day 53</a> - <a href="#day54">day 54</a> - <a href="#day55">day 55</a> - <a href="#day56">day 56</a> - <a href="#day57">day 57</a> - <a href="#day58">day 58</a> - <a href="#day59">day 59</a><br>
        <a href="#finalstats">final stats</a><br>
        <hr>
        </div>


        <div class="block">
        <a name="day1" class="day">day 1 - Port of Roosville to 'Sons of Rest' slide - (august 1st, 2005)</a><br>
        <div class="stats">34.65 miles - 5:34 hours - 6.2 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: my first day; tons of mixed feelings: excitement, loneliness, happiness, anxiousness; huckleberry
        milkshake in Eureka; not making the days recommended mileage; setting up camp for the first time
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314752/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/30/51314752_590301b465_o.jpg" alt="welcome to Montana" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">'welcome to Montana'" - only 2,500 miles to go</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314732/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/33/51314732_22a9427c2e_o.jpg" alt="bike on the side of the road" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">my bike and gear all shiny and clean</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314741/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51314741_f4cc4b3ab0_o.jpg" alt="llama" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">my first 'wildlife' sighting - a lone llama</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314750/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/32/51314750_734b18561d_o.jpg" alt="turkeys" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">wild turkeys lurking</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314735/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/32/51314735_11c42df074_o.jpg" alt="deer" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the first of hundreds of deer i would see</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day2" class="day">day 2 - 'Sons of Rest' slide to Red Meadow Creek</a><br>
        <div class="stats">39.84 miles - 6:42 hours - 5.9 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: rare early start; filtering water successfully (which made me confident that i
        could rely on myself and i wouldnt die out in the woods); fast, rocky descent; not sleeping
        on the side of the road; feeling sick and considering giving up
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314857/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/28/51314857_6a5e9fada1_o.jpg" alt="grave creek" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">Grave Creek - my first water source</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314851/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/28/51314851_b9a89b54f3_o.jpg" alt="under the grave creek bridge" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">cool view from under the Grave Creek bridge</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day3" class="day">day 3 - Red Meadow Lake to Whitefish, MT</a><br>
        <div class="stats">33.92 miles - 4:23 hours - 7.7 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: red meadow lake was gorgeous; only having a single snickers bar to eat all day;
        long descent into Whitefish; having a pizza and a beer at a restaurant; deciding that i
        could do this
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314889/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51314889_3c5631628f_o.jpg" alt="campsite" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">my minimalist campsite</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314891/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/28/51314891_c1929a7075_o.jpg" alt="red meadow lake" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">situated high in the forest, Red Meadow Lake was beautiful</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day4" class="day">day 4 - Whitefish, MT to Bigfork, MT</a><br>
        <div class="stats">45.59 miles - 5.23 hours - 8.4 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: hot sun and a nasty sunburn; dry, dusty gravel roads; first 40+ mile ride; fun trail
        from Swan Lake to Bigfork; getting a real meal at the end of a hard day; camping (perhaps
        illegally) in the city park
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day5" class="day">day 5 - Bigfork, MT to Fatty Creek Road</a><br>
        <div class="stats">34.78 miles - 5.31 hours - 6.3 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: hot day again; tough climb; fun descent; getting low on water; riding in the dark
        because i couldnt find a good campsite
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315177/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/33/51315177_f7e3e99370_o.jpg" alt="great divide trail sign" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption" style="width:480px;">a biker-friendly family offered water, camping, and a rest stop for wary riders</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315186/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/30/51315186_9a92f473f6_o.jpg" alt="yellow field" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">a field of brilliant yellow flowers</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315163/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51315163_9f9d049805_o.jpg" alt="moose" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the only moose i saw on the trip</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315155/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51315155_0abdf7b846_o.jpg" alt="my bike enjoying the shade" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">my bike taking a break in the shade</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day6" class="day">day 6 - Fatty Creek Road to Holland Lake</a><br>
        <div class="stats">41.05 miles - 6:04 hours - 6.7 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: awesome singletrack through forests and meadows; arriving at Holland Lake lodge only
        to find that there was a private wedding there and no food was being served
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315201/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/32/51315201_9e3216bdcd_o.jpg" alt="me" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">self-portrait (at the beginning of the day because i am still smiling)</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315248/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/28/51315248_0a57a5519a_o.jpg" alt="mossy waterfall" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">a cool mossy waterfall</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315252/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/30/51315252_50b9d50cdf_o.jpg" alt="road through the woods" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">a peaceful ride through the cool forest is not the worst way to spend a day</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315239/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/32/51315239_a33811042f_o.jpg" alt="miniature christmas trees" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">miniature christmas trees in training</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315266/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/24/51315266_be16788255_o.jpg" alt="singletrack" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">some great singletrack through the woods</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315234/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51315234_bf981d4a80_o.jpg" alt="me and my bike" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">me and my bike getting ready to hit the singletrack</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day7" class="day">day 7 - Holland Lake to Seely Lake, MT</a><br>
        <div class="stats">34.39 miles - 4:28 hours - 7.7 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: first deviation from the mapped route; another huckleberry milkshake; bored with
        seeing deer; sleeping under the stars
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315269/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/24/51315269_674c4bda35_o.jpg" alt="deer in town" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">deer were everywhere, even right in town. i finally tired of taking pictures of them</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day8" class="day">day 8 - Seely Lake, MT to Huckleberry Mountain</a><br>
        <div class="stats">45.27 miles - 6:18 hours - 7.1 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: long day; resting in Ovanda (population: about 50, dogs: about 100); long gravel roads;
        finding a hidden campsite; dreading a hard day tomorrow
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315282/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/31/51315282_28cff17c5d_o.jpg" alt="trailer loaded with gear" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">BOB carrying the load</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315275/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/31/51315275_5dcd546f00_o.jpg" alt="dogsled trail" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">don't worry, dogsledding IS allowed on this trail</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315278/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/24/51315278_eaf5ec9a11_o.jpg" alt="farm sunset" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">sun setting on the wide-open ranchlands of northern Montana</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day9" class="day">day 9 - Huckleberry Mountain to Lincoln, MT</a><br>
        <div class="stats">26.86 miles - 4:20 hours - 6.1 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: met a couple of young guys who worked for the forest service; 6-mile climb up Huckleberry
        Mountain; finding out the climb wasnt so bad after all; incredibly bumpy washboard roads; finding
        out Lincoln is the home of the Unibomber; choosing from an extensive menu of: hamburgers, cheeseburgers,
        or bacon burgers
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day10" class="day">day 10 - Lincoln, MT to Deadman's Creek</a><br>
        <div class="stats">30.23 miles - 4:45 hours - 6.3 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: tough 4-mile alternate trail deep in the forest with several stream crossings; bear
        sighting; first continental divide crossing; first time i got rained on; not finding the
        recommended campsite; setting up camp in a place where i knew there were bears; playing the
        harmonica; nighttime visit from a bear
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314618/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/27/51314618_84a2f541b0_o.jpg" alt="stream crossing" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">an incredible stretch of trail, including 4 stream crossings</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314573/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51314573_ee47fed0e8_o.jpg" alt="my bike after crossing the stream" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">my bike and BOB taking a rest after crossing some streams</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314583/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/28/51314583_0f04f83b54_o.jpg" alt="first continental divide crossing" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">finally, my first continental divide crossing</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314591/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/24/51314591_0eea7fdffd_o.jpg" alt="me looking worn out after my first divide crossing" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">a little worn out, but happy to have made my first divide crossing</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day11" class="day">day 11 - Deadman's Creek to Helena, MT</a><br>
        <div class="stats">35.74 miles - 5:35 hours - 6.4 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: super early start; vowing to never visit Deadman's Creek again; first taste of riding
        into the wind and on pavement; getting a hotel room and taking a shower
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day12" class="day">day 12 - Helena, MT</a><br>
        <div class="stats">REST DAY</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: cloudy and rainy; having to decide to take an unplanned rest day; spending most of
        the day sitting in a restaurant
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day13" class="day">day 13 - Helena, MT to Park Lake</a><br>
        <div class="stats">23.04 miles - 4:49 hours - 4.7 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: looking forward to a super short day; feeling more tired after a day off; walking up
        a majority of a tough climb; finding out that my recommended campground was closed because the
        nearby dam had a crack in it
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314630/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/30/51314630_1e18e5bb43_o.jpg" alt="too many signs" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">a few too many signs</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314627/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/28/51314627_e1ae86e0d9_o.jpg" alt="great divide mountain bike route sign" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption" style="width:480px;">a cool Great Divide Mountain Bike Route trail sign</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day14" class="day">day 14 - Park Lake to Butte, MT</a><br>
        <div class="stats">46.52 miles - 6:34 hours - 7.0 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: very long day; 3-mile mostly hike-a-bike over Lava Mountain; ran into a group of 4-wheel
        drives doing a trail run; awesome descent down Uncle Sam Creek canyon; lucking out that the only
        restaurant in Basin was open on a sunday; non-maintained cattle access trail; taking a nap in the
        middle of the ride; first bad taste of frontage roads; scary fast descent on the interstate into
        Butte
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314670/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/30/51314670_f0c2de9a76_o.jpg" alt="lava mountain rocky trail" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the Lava Mountain trail was rocky and steep and great mountain biking - if you arent dragging an extra 80 lbs. behind you</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314655/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51314655_7079336cd1_o.jpg" alt="old mine" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">one of many old abandoned mines in Montana</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314668/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/31/51314668_0839451fe1_o.jpg" alt="rocky stream" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption" style="width:480px;">a rocky and rugged mountain stream</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314651/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/32/51314651_3faca88c20_o.jpg" alt="me and a rocky stream" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">me and the stream</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314637/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/31/51314637_548cb56c4e_o.jpg" alt="non-maintained cattle access trail sign" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">what exactly is a 'Non-maintained cattle access trail' anyway?</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314639/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51314639_7c2a12bcb8_o.jpg" alt="another divide crossing" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">another divide crossing, with the elevation starting to creep up</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day15" class="day">day 15 - Butte, MT to Beaver Dam Campground</a><br>
        <div class="stats">36.79 miles - 5:37 hours - 6.5 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: having to replace my seat; another tough climb; laying on my back and looking at the clouds;
        seeing an eagle; having to mentally and physically grind out the last 6 miles before dark; looking
        forward to having other campers in the campground (not that i talk to them, but i found myself hoping
        for their presence anyway)
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314682/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/31/51314682_8fc7545d6d_o.jpg" alt="overlooking Butte" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">overlooking Butte from up on high</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314678/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/31/51314678_a1e9909e3c_o.jpg" alt="golden eagle" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">a golden eagle checking me out</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day16" class="day">day 16 - Beaver Dam Campground to Little Joe Campground</a><br>
        <div class="stats">37.35 miles - 5:17 hours - 7.0 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: super hard climb, including the first time the map instructed to 'push your bike up the hill';
        deciding to try to ride the Fleecer ridge descent that the map warned against; finding out that BOB
        is tricky on the super steep stuff because he has no brakes; feeling good after i rode the 'toughest
        hill (up or down)' on the whole trail; meeting Steve & Agnes (and Emma the dog) and having a good
        conversation with them
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314705/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/24/51314705_b3df259041_o.jpg" alt="forest meadow" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">a forest meadow with a gorgeous view</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314702/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/28/51314702_1d689a34bf_o.jpg" alt="fleecer ridge descent" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the infamous Fleecer Ridge descent (waaaaaay steeper than it looks in this picture)</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314691/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/26/51314691_44095728fa_o.jpg" alt="cattle gang" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the real Montana street gang</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day17" class="day">day 17 - Little Joe Campground to Grant, MT</a><br>
        <div class="stats">48.71 miles - 6:04 hours - 8.0 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: Steve & Agnes' incredible generosity; missing out on a good downhill because of construction;
        getting caught trying to avoid the pilot car; first ride in a vehicle in over 2 weeks; missing out on
        a soak in the hot springs; little bit of refreshing rain; hammering it on the pavement; forging on
        past my recommended campsite; finding an unexpected cafe in Grant; meeting Jack & Jim, two awesome
        guys who even shared their room with me
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314707/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/32/51314707_61449ec3b0_o.jpg" alt="lonely road from bannack to grants" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">long lonely road across southern Montana's wide open space</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314710/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/31/51314710_101134b1b7_o.jpg" alt="me" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">still looking rough, but happy</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day18" class="day">day 18 - Grant, MT to Lima, MT</a><br>
        <div class="stats">70.09 miles - 8:44 hours - 8.0 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: meeting some folks doing a faithful re-enactment of the entire Lewis & Clark expedition (including
        building a ship and making dugout canoes, etc); being in the middle of nowhere; deciding to ride 2
        days worth in one day
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314730/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51314730_9fa42f2362_o.jpg" alt="jim and jack" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">jim and jack, biking a Montana portion of the Lewis & Clark trail, loaded up and ready to take on Lemhi Pass</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314715/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/33/51314715_43fa0d467c_o.jpg" alt="old bannack road" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the Old Bannack Road in the middle of nowhere</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314719/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/24/51314719_4093eab526_o.jpg" alt="big sky" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">big sky is abundant in Montana</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314725/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/31/51314725_63c361e011_o.jpg" alt="impassable when wet" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">luckily, it only rained for about 15 minutes this day</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day19" class="day">day 19 - Lima, MT to Red Rocks Wildlife Refuge</a><br>
        <div class="stats">57.77 miles - 7:22 hours - 7.8 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: late start; lots of gravel; having to push it to get to my camp before it was too dark;
        realizing i was getting much stronger
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day20" class="day">day 20 - Red Rocks Wildlife Refuge to Island Park, ID</a><br>
        <div class="stats">30.06 miles - 4:02 hours - 7.4 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: seeing some Trumpeter swans (even if it was from a *very* far distance); completing my ride
        through Montana and entering Idaho; seeing a bald eagle; Rob & Faye offering me a place to camp because
        it got too dark to continue riding
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314756/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/24/51314756_e89724835b_o.jpg" alt="hell roaring creek" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">pretty cool to think that the water in this creek flows all the way to the Atlantic Ocean</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314759/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51314759_0ba6596500_o.jpg" alt="montana-idaho border" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">20 days gone by and i had ridden through the entire state of Montana</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day21" class="day">day 21 - Island Park, ID to Warm River Campground</a><br>
        <div class="stats">36.15 miles - 4:11 hours - 8.6 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: soft, bumpy old railroad bed; realizing the book's description of this portion of the trail
        as being 'tedious' was spot on; incredible views of the Warm River; the last section of the trail was
        a fun descent with wildflowers and an old tunnel; being warned by the campground host to watch out for
        skunks
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314766/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/28/51314766_23b7e5a10d_o.jpg" alt="warm river" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the last portion of the ride today had great views of the rugged Warm River below</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314773/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/24/51314773_bacdfa6d9f_o.jpg" alt="tunnel" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">since the trail today followed an old railroad bed, i got to pass through this cool old tunnel</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day22" class="day">day 22 - Warm River Campground to Flagg Ranch, WY</a><br>
        <div class="stats">48.45 miles - 6:36 hours - 7.3 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: potato fields; unexpected lunch at Squirrel Meadows Ranch; first views of the Tetons; finishing
        Idaho and entering Wyoming and not even knowing it; riding along the edge of Yellowstone; incredible
        scenery; narrowly missing a wicked thunderstorm; meeting a couple from California at dinner who took
        my picture and called my mom to tell her i was doing good
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314775/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/30/51314775_2fb59ae40b_o.jpg" alt="lilypad covered lake" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">this big lake was about 90% covered in lily pads</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day23" class="day">day 23 - Flagg Ranch, WY to Togwotee Village, WY</a><br>
        <div class="stats">45.09 miles - 6:54 hours - 6.5 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: having to ride on the pavement all day; cars and RVs whizzing within inches of my handlebars;
        stunning views of the Tetons; meeting a guy (Mike) riding the TransAmerica trail from Washington, DC to
        Portland, OR; finding out that Blackrock Bicycle campground was non-existent; struggling up an additional
        4 miles to Togwotee Village in the dark; having the best meal of the ride and an ice cream sunday to
        top it off; having to find my campsite and set up camp in the pitch black
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314787/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/26/51314787_24bfec7bef_o.jpg" alt="me entering teton national park" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">even though i had to ride on the road most of the day, the road ran through Grand Teton National Park so it was very scenic</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314788/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51314788_7ee1ff4221_o.jpg" alt="tetons up close" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the Tetons literally rise straight up from the lake below, no foothills at all</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314781/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51314781_1993e90da3_o.jpg" alt="be bear aware" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">some good advice</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day24" class="day">day 24 - Togwotee Village, WY to Union Pass</a><br>
        <div class="stats">43.11 miles - 6:26 hours - 6.7 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: losing my rain jacket; finding my rain jacket; looooong climb up Togwotee Pass; meeting a family
        from France who had a son who had riding his bike around the world and trekked across Africa; fast
        descent on pavement; climbing the 2nd pass of the day; wind that almost blew me over; turning down a
        ride up the hill; finding an awesome primitive campsite
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314791/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/26/51314791_58977ffc76_o.jpg" alt="divide crossing" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">yet another divide crossing, elevation still going up, up, up</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day25" class="day">day 25 - Union Pass to Cora, WY</a><br>
        <div class="stats">40.86 miles - 5:37 hours - 7.2 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: more wind; feeling a little bit sick; finding the tree carving from the first group to ride
        this trail; skipping my campsite to find some real food; stumbling upon 'The Place' restaurant
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314798/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51314798_dcb49d8bd1_o.jpg" alt="'ride the divide' carving" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption" style="width:480px;">the first group to ever ride this route carved this back in 1998</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314806/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51314806_20b0064b05_o.jpg" alt="'ride the divide' carving close-up" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the hair is close, but i wasnt going that fast</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314809/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/30/51314809_500181eb01_o.jpg" alt="me at mosquito lake" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">this is what i would look like if you were only two inches tall</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day26" class="day">day 26 - Cora, WY to Pinedale, WY</a><br>
        <div class="stats">28.88 miles - 2:48 hours - 10.2 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: short ride; trying to see how fast i could go; finding out that all of the hotel rooms were
        booked by oil companies who were drilling in the area; finally finding a family-run hotel tucked in
        by a creek that held their rooms for tourist only (no oil employees); feeling like i went back in time
        in the local grocery/sporting goods store
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day27" class="day">day 27 - Pinedale, WY to Little Sandy Creek</a><br>
        <div class="stats">50.57 miles - 6:18 hours - 8.0 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: headed out for a 135-mile stretch through the Great Basin desert; running into two seperate
        people looking for a lake in the middle of the desert; meeting Mike & Birdie, two Californian hippies
        who had just sold their house and were touring around the country living out of their camper; setting
        up camp in the dark
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314813/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/24/51314813_fef54c6bbd_o.jpg" alt="headed into great basin" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">headed into the Great Basin</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314828/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/30/51314828_f84e4a302f_o.jpg" alt="nightfall in the desert" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">nightfall in the desert</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day28" class="day">day 28 - Little Sandy Creek to Sweetwater River</a><br>
        <div class="stats">48.51 miles - 6:02 hours - 8.0 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: just a lot of pedalling through the desert; finding a neat place to camp right next to the river
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314829/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51314829_d49cc58e8e_o.jpg" alt="sweetwater river campsite" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">an oasis in the desert</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314817/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/24/51314817_20dd4344fe_o.jpg" alt="sweetwater river campsite close-up" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">life is pretty good</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day29" class="day">day 29 - Sweetwater River to Rawlings, WY</a><br>
        <div class="stats">116.31 miles - 15:46 hours - 8.4 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: long day riding through the desert; no water sources for 70 miles; more wind; deciding
        to skip the cow-patty campground and continue riding to (what i thought was) a town; seeing
        a herd of wild horses; finding out my 'town' was just a single condemned-looking building;
        stupidly deciding to try to continue to Rawlings even though it was dark and 33 miles away;
        running completely out of water; contemplating just lying down and dying on the side of the road;
        watching the cars tail lights keep going up and up the never-ending hill; finally getting to
        Rawlings at 2:15am; being super dehydrated; getting a room at a super sleezy looking motel;
        deciding to quit my ride
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314844/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51314844_6e4465e865_o.jpg" alt="oregon trail/pony express marker" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption" style="width:480px;">lots of history running through this area</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314838/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/30/51314838_08965f94bf_o.jpg" alt="oregon trail/mormon pioneer marker" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption" style="width:480px;">this picture doesnt show it, but you could still see the old wagon ruts from the original trails</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day30" class="day">day 30 - Rawlings, WY</a><br>
        <div class="stats">REST DAY</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: trying to recover from yesterday; spending the day in the library reading about rivers and
        canoe-camping; deciding to try to keep going with my ride
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day31" class="day">day 31 - Rawlings, WY to Middlewood Hill</a><br>
        <div class="stats">32.56 miles - 4:51 hours - 6.7 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: struggling with the ride right from the start; deciding to just try to do 30 of the 55 miles
        planned for the day; incredibly steep gravel hills; trying to hide my campsite because i didnt know
        if it was private property or not
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day32" class="day">day 32 - Middlewood Hill to Routt National Forest</a><br>
        <div class="stats">56.46 miles - 8:03 hours - 7.0 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: more climbing; finally getting back into the forest and out of the desert; a complete stranger
        offering me all of his ice water; Aspen Alley; private property everywhere; trying desperately to get
        back onto public lands before dark; getting too dark to even ride my bike; having a guy (Peter - the
        chef at the huge guest ranch down the road) stop to make sure i was doing alright and help me set up
        my camp
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day33" class="day">day 33 - Routt National Forest to Steamboat Springs, CO</a><br>
        <div class="stats">43.48 miles - 5:12 hours - 8.3 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: single-minded vision on making it to Steamboat Springs today; very steep climb; enjoying
        cold water while watching the hummingbirds; finding out that 'all down hill' isnt; some good
        nachos at Hahn's Peak cafe; passing a hiker; arriving in Steamboat Springs - my unofficial
        halfway point (actually, just past halfway); re-meeting the hiker from earlier in the day and
        having him offer me a spare bed in his hotel room; hearing stories of hiking in the Alaskan
        wilderness
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day34" class="day">day 34 - Steamboat Springs, CO</a><br>
        <div class="stats">REST DAY</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: laundry; meeting Dan who wanted to sell his house in Florida and come ride with me; hanging
        out in the park most of the day; getting to see Michaleen for the first time in over a month
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day35" class="day">day 35 - Steamboat Springs, CO</a><br>
        <div class="stats">REST DAY</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: riding the gondola up the mountain; relaxing in the grass; chinese food; making marshmallow-
        roasting sticks; sitting on the porch in the rain; roasting marshmallows over my pathetic excuse for
        a fire
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314868/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51314868_2e416503c7_o.jpg" alt="girls in steamboat springs" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">relaxing at the top of the gondola in Steamboat Springs</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day36" class="day">day 36 - Steamboat Springs, CO to Lynx Pass</a><br>
        <div class="stats">42.28 miles - 6:15 hours - 6.7 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: fun ride along a creek; crossing a dam; some singletrack around the lake; the bridge
        being out; noticing bike tracks and wondering if i would meet someone else doing the ride;
        meeting Craig & Sheri who were riding from Steamboat Springs to Winterpark
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day37" class="day">day 37 - Lynx Pass to Kremmling, CO</a><br>
        <div class="stats">34.21 miles - 4:32 hours - 7.1 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: late start; wondering if i would catch up to Craig & Sheri; fording a deep stream;
        meeting up with Craig & Sheri again; enjoying riding with some people to talk to; some tough
        hills and then a steep descent; lunch on the Colorado River; dreading a big hill; helping
        Craig & Sheri hitch a ride into town; hammering the remainder of the ride before dark;
        Craig & Sheri borrowing the hotel's van to come back and get me; Craig & Sheri renting a
        cabin with an extra pull-out bed so i had a place to stay; steak dinner
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314873/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/33/51314873_4491563f00_o.jpg" alt="craig and sheri" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">craig and sheri - they were doing a 5-day bike tour along this portion of the route from Steamboat Springs to Winterpark</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day38" class="day">day 38 - Kremmling, CO to Blue River Campground</a><br>
        <div class="stats">45.76 miles - 5:37 hours - 8.1 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: saying goodbye to Craig & Sheri; long climb up Ute Pass; fast descent down pavement;
        stopping short of my destination because i was beat
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day39" class="day">day 39 - Blue River Campground to Frisco, CO</a><br>
        <div class="stats">16.84 miles - 2:04 hours - 8.1 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: eating pizza for lunch; riding the awesome bike path from Dillion to Frisco; getting
        rained out; spending the day in the Frisco brewpub; talking to the locals about how cool it is
        to live there; getting a hotel and hoping the weather tomorrow was better; shortest day so far
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314878/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/28/51314878_8ae2a3bbfa_o.jpg" alt="steep bike hill sign" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">this sign totally sums up my trip</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day40" class="day">day 40 - Frisco, CO to Hartsel, CO</a><br>
        <div class="stats">51.37 miles - 6:24 hours - 8.0 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: early start; riding through the forest in the morning was awesome; the bike path from
        Frisco to Breckinridge was fun; finding out that the climb up 11,500 foot Boreas Pass was not
        really that bad; getting rained on again; taking shelter in an old railroad car; getting a ride
        down the mountain from a friendly ranger; setting the top speed of the ride (38.5 mph); first
        taste of the flat, treeless areas of South Park; tons of wind; arriving in Hartsel to find out
        that the only restaurant in town only serves food until 4pm; camping in the back lot of the local
        bar with dogs barking all night
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314895/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/32/51314895_4d1ea4069b_o.jpg" alt="aspens are turning" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the aspens were starting to turn and the scenery was beautiful</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day41" class="day">day 41 - Hartsel, CO to Salida, CO</a><br>
        <div class="stats">48.13 miles - 6:58 hours - 6.9 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: more wind; hating wind; more boring areas of Colorado; super fast descent into Salida; Scot
        at Absolute Bikes fixing up my bike, giving me tips on where to eat, and offering to let me stay on
        their back porch; falling asleep to the jazz coming from the place next door
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314903/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/32/51314903_e8d4465939_o.jpg" alt="me and some rocks" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">just me and some rocks</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314898/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/28/51314898_a42bbf9633_o.jpg" alt="collegiate peaks" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">kind of hard to see, but these are the Collegiate Peaks, a bunch of 14,000 ft. mountains</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day42" class="day">day 42 - Salida, CO to Marshall Pass</a><br>
        <div class="stats">33.27 miles - 5:15 hours - 6.3 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: big, long pass that ended up being not too bad to climb; crossing the Colorado Trail; starting
        to plan my next adventure (kayaking trip); weather is starting to get cold at night
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314909/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51314909_cc864ca88a_o.jpg" alt="marshall pass" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">note the elevation, still going up. it was getting a little chilly up here as well</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day43" class="day">day 43 - Marshall Pass to Dome Lake</a><br>
        <div class="stats">47.18 miles - 6:00 hours - 7.8 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: more !@#$% wind!; exotic animal ranch with white elk, reindeer, and yaks
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314946/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/28/51314946_d821587f58_o.jpg" alt="white elk" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">white elk</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314955/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51314955_71cba1c616_o.jpg" alt="white elk" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">another white elk</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314930/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51314930_466a3e1917_o.jpg" alt="reindeer" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">reindeer</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314935/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/33/51314935_743e54068b_o.jpg" alt="reindeer" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">another reindeer</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314925/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51314925_61303e8dfa_o.jpg" alt="reindeer" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">last reindeer</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314921/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/33/51314921_9008f0af13_o.jpg" alt="rock rings" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">this rock had rings, almost like the rings in a tree. i thought it was cool</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day44" class="day">day 44 - Dome Lake to Storm King Campground</a><br>
        <div class="stats">41.04 miles - 5:35 hours - 7.3 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: back into the forest finally; climbing two 10,000+ ft. passes (Cochetopa and Carnero); over
        1700 miles already ridden
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314967/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51314967_a9de7257d9_o.jpg" alt="rock column" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption" style="width:480px;">this area had some really neat rock formations</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314971/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/30/51314971_cd1ae6288f_o.jpg" alt="rocks" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">more cool looking rocks</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day45" class="day">day 45 - Storm King Campground to Del Norte, CO</a><br>
        <div class="stats">28.44 miles - 3:24 hours - 8.3 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: the worst wind of the trip
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day46" class="day">day 46 - Del Norte, CO to Stunner Campground</a><br>
        <div class="stats">42.28 miles - 7:01 hours - 6.0 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: big day - had to climb up 11,900 foot Indiana Pass; for being the biggest hill of the trip, i
        just slowly and surely rode up it; contaminated Summitville; trying to get to camp before dark; getting
        really really cold on the final descent
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314989/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/24/51314989_ae483e8584_o.jpg" alt="purple and yellow flowers" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">purple and yellow flowers in a field</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314975/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/31/51314975_1ea549c156_o.jpg" alt="indiana pass 11,900 ft" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the highest point of my trip, and no sign! 11,900 foot Indiana Pass</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315282/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51314997_fe16521065_o.jpg" alt="contaminated water at summitville" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the Summitville area is all contaminated from decades of mining. it was pretty evident from the color of the water</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314997/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/33/51315001_3d2cb3acc0_o.jpg" alt="over-mined summitville peak" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">hard to see here, but over half of that mountain in the background has been mined away</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315001/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/31/51314981_4a00d3a259_o.jpg" alt="nightfall" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">riding through the forest at night is one of the coolest feelings in the world</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51314977/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/33/51314977_04cf12a891_o.jpg" alt="moon" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">just the moon</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day47" class="day">day 47 - Stunner Campground to Platoro, CO</a><br>
        <div class="stats">6.76 miles - 1:07 hours - 5.9 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: shortest ride of the trip; the wind was fierce and that made it very cold as well; warming
        up by the fire at the Platoro Cafe; the incredibly nice lady that ran the lodge offereing me a free
        room for the night ("its going to go empty anyway" she said); warm peach cobbler with ice cream (x2)
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day48" class="day">day 48 - Platoro, CO to Colorado/New Mexico border</a><br>
        <div class="stats">37.65 miles - 4:41 hours - 8.0 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: more wind (notice a pattern?); chicken and broccoli fettucine in Horca; last night in Colorado
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315015/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/31/51315015_a4123b1b8f_o.jpg" alt="last day in colorado" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">my last night in colorado</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315019/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/33/51315019_bd2bdb3626_o.jpg" alt="me" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">obligatory mug shot</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315022/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51315022_079b45c624_o.jpg" alt="more sunny mountains" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">some sunny mountains</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day49" class="day">day 49 - Colorado/New Mexico border to Cuba, NM</a> (off-route)<br>
        <div class="stats">85.41 miles - 8:40 hours - 9.8 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: bummed that i wouldnt get to see the Cumbres & Toltec coal engine; ending up getting to
        see it anyway; long downhill into Charma; deciding to take an alternate route to Cuba because of
        potential rain, bypassing Abiqui and cutting up to 3 days off my ride; feeling guilty about taking
        the alternate route; finding out there was a big fire near Abiqui and feeling better about my route;
        pounding the pavement for the first half of the ride; pushing past my intended campsite; surrounded
        by private property and nowhere to camp; riding through the dark, hoping each little spot on the map
        might be a town; deciding to ride all the way to Cuba; making it to Cuba in time to have a great
        dinner at a Mexican restaurant
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315040/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/33/51315040_c4ca20f7d9_o.jpg" alt="welcome to New Mexico" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">only one more state to go!</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315037/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/33/51315037_f02a12fc09_o.jpg" alt="cumbres & toltec locomotive" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the Cumbres & Toltec locomotive chugging up Cumbres Pass</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315032/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/28/51315032_dd29e0c39f_o.jpg" alt="cumbres & toltec locomotive" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">there is actually a guy in there shoveling coal as fast as he can to keep the train going. sometimes they have to try two or three times to make it up the pass</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day50" class="day">day 50 - Cuba, NM to Whitehorse, NM</a><br>
        <div class="stats">53.49 miles - 5:43 hours - 9.3 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: not looking forward to 2 long days of riding on the pavement; getting a tip on an off-road
        alternate to my already alternate route; riding across the reservation with no idea where i am going
        and no map to tell me how to get there; hiding my campsite just in case i wasnt supposed to be there
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315048/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/33/51315048_5a5a605bc2_o.jpg" alt="sunset" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">an amazing sunset over the Navajo reservation</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day51" class="day">day 51 - Whitehorse, NM to Grants, NM</a><br>
        <div class="stats">59.66 miles - 5:52 hours - 10.1 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: just racking up the miles on the pavement; starting to think about the end of the trip;
        chinese food for dinner
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day52" class="day">day 52 - Grants, NM to Homestead Canyon</a><br>
        <div class="stats">45.69 miles - 5:04 hours - 9.0 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: starting a 6-day stretch between Grants and Silver City; met a guy hiking the Continental
        Divide who had left the Canadian border on June 13th; cool scenery; just enjoying the ride and not
        looking at my odometer
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315052/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/32/51315052_eb8f945fd3_o.jpg" alt="La Ventana natural arch" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">La Ventana ("The Window") natural arch in El Malpais National Monument</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day53" class="day">day 53 - Homestead Canyon to Pie Town, NM</a><br>
        <div class="stats">31.99 miles - 4:08 hours - 7.7 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: looking forward to the famous Pie Town; met another guy hiking the CDT; ate lunch and two
        pieces of pie as i watch it start pouring rain right after i got inside; lost my fleece sweatshirt;
        found my fleece sweatshirt; spent the afternoon relaxing
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315059/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51315059_0f8c70ba56_o.jpg" alt="Pie Town" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">Pie Town, serving up...pie</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315056/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/33/51315056_15a92f185d_o.jpg" alt="Daily Pie Cafe" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">The Daily Pie, where i got some...pie</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day54" class="day">day 54 - Pie Town, NM to Gila National Forest</a><br>
        <div class="stats">49.10 miles - 6:03 hours - 8.1 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: trying to get to Silver City as fast as possible; fell asleep to coyotes howling
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day55" class="day">day 55 - Gila National Forest to Wall Lake</a><br>
        <div class="stats">58.85 miles - 6:58 hours - 8.4 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: long day; 'small reservoir' water source listed in the book turned out to be a big mud puddle;
        way out in the middle of nowhere, wondering if maybe i took a wrong turn; finding out my intended
        campground no longer existed; riding in the dark; falling asleep to elk bugling
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day56" class="day">day 56 - Wall Lake to Rocky Canyon Campground</a><br>
        <div class="stats">25.50 miles - 4:32 hours - 5.6 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: very, very steep, rocky hills; soaked in a cool stream; weather is getting hot
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day57" class="day">day 57 - Rocky Canyon Campground to Silver City, NM</a><br>
        <div class="stats">44.05 miles - 4:45 hours - 9.2 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: last big climb of the trip; met a guy who had ridden the trail on a motorcycle (cheater) =);
        fun zip down the Mimbres River canyon; hot climb up the Georgetown road; first flat tire just as i
        rode into Silver City
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315072/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/26/51315072_53153b659b_o.jpg" alt="Santa Rita pit mine" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">the Santa Rita pit mine - this picture doesnt represent how increbibly *huge* this thing is</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day58" class="day">day 58 - Silver City, NM to Hachita, NM</a><br>
        <div class="stats">80.95 miles - 8:21 hours - 9.7 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: another flat tire just after leaving Silver City; finally getting off of the pavement; riding
        through the desert; trying to ride as fast as i could to make it to Hachita before dark; free beers and
        a place to stay thanks to the owner of the only business in Hachita
        </div>
        (no pictures)<br>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="day59" class="day">day 59 - Hachita, NM to Antelope Wells, NM - (september 28th, 2005)</a><br>
        <div class="stats">46.11 miles - 4:36 hours - 10.0 avg.</div>
        <div class="desc">
        summary: dilly-dally start; trying to ride slow; nothing but flat road ahead and sagebrush in every
        direction; two flat tires at the same time (all four flats were in the last 3 days of my ride);
        reminiscing on the trip; counting down the final miles; arriving at Antelope Wells; seeing Michaleen;
        heading home
        </div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315078/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51315078_623d336dde_o.jpg" alt="Antelope Wells" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">i had been waiting to see this sign for almost two months</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315083/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51315083_34b68e3637_o.jpg" alt="my bike made it" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">my bike and BOB get all of the credit</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315128/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/25/51315128_f63b182b86_o.jpg" alt="penalty: prison" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">penalty: prison!</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315132/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/31/51315132_799558b0c2_o.jpg" alt="port of Antelope Wells" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">de nada</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315142/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/30/51315142_4e996eef0c_o.jpg" alt="US-Mexico border" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">US/Mexico border</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315116/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/28/51315116_39e4bb0964_o.jpg" alt="i am in Mexico" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">a very short trip into Mexico</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315094/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/31/51315094_658d8b2dd8_o.jpg" alt="Antelope Wells...finally!" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">Antelope Wells - i made it!</div>
        <a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/briandunnington/51315087/"><img src="http://static.flickr.com/29/51315087_aa6fc7ea10_o.jpg" alt="final mileage" /></a><br>
        <div align="center" class="caption">all in all, i rode 2401 miles (my odometer already had 134 miles on it when i started)</div>
        </div>

        <div class="block">
        <a name="finalstats" class="day">final stats:</a><br>
        <div class="stats">2401 miles - 315:15 hours - 7.6 avg.</div>
        <div class="stats">longest day: 116.31 miles (Sweetwater River to Rawlings, WY)</div>
        <div class="stats">shortest day: 6.76 miles (Stunner Campground to Platoro, CO)</div>
        <div class="stats">59 days, including 4 rest days</div>
        </div>
</div>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2005 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/great_divide_ride</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/greatdivideride_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>That Malty Molly</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/malty_molly</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/malty_molly.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><div style="BORDER: #aab29d 4px solid; PADDING: 10px; background-color:#256040;color:#948f29;margin-right:20px;"><span style="font-size:120%;">That Malty Molly</span><p style="color:#948F29;">She blew into my life during Octoberfest and while our back-and-forth only lasted a month, I feel like I have known her all my life. Molly's the type of red-head that does not take things seriously, but when it comes to making beer, she believes that additives and ales don't mix.</p><p style="color:#948F29;">When I think back on this full-bodied lass, all that I can say is that she was dying to get out...and I just couldn't keep her contained. </p></div>

<div><img src="/img/beerworks/molly.png" /></div>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2005 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/malty_molly</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/malty_molly_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>New Bike</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/new_bike</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/greatdivideride.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Only a few weeks until I depart on my <a href="http://greatdivideride.blogspot.com">big adventure</a> and I just got one of the most important pieces of gear.</p>

<p><img src="/img/greatdivideride/bike_with_trailer2.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

<p><img src="/img/greatdivideride/bike1.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2005 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/new_bike</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/greatdivideride_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stop-motion Study 3 - Sound</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/lego_study_3</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_3.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Well, I am not following my original plan at all as far as what aspects of stop-motion animation I would explore next, but I am having fun, so who cares. Today I decided to try experimenting with sound in my films. specifically, I wanted to try sound effects, foley (background sound), and soundtrack music.</p>

<p>First stop - <a href="http://www.brickfilms.com/resources.php">brickfilms.com</a>. Their 'resources' section lead me to an awesome free sound editing/mixing program called <a href="http://audacity.sourceforge.net/about/">Audacity</a>. It can do all kinds of cool stuff (most of which is way over my head), but the main thing it can do is edit and mix multiple audio tracks.</p>

<p>Ok, next stop - <a href="http://findsounds.com">findsounds.com</a>. Josh turned me on to this site where there are tons and tons of free sound effects available. But wait, what sounds do I need? Hmm, I just realized I have no movie to work from, nor any idea what type of movie I will even be making. Oh well, let's just get some good generic sound effects and go from there. I got a door bell, knocking on a door, a door opening, and a door closing. That should work into a plot somehow. Wait, I need foley sounds. What better background sound than some birds chirping (to be specific, these were house finches, at least according to the site. I had my choice of warblers, swallows, red-throated loons, white-eyed vireos, and many more, but nothing could beat some good old-fashioned house finches).</p>

<p>Before I even attempted to integrate any of these sounds into a movie, I fired up Audacity and played around with it. It was a little confusing at first because I didnt know how to adjust the time of the sounds, but once I found the 'Time Shift' tool, it was a piece of cake. So I put the birds chirping on a loop, added the doorbell sound, followed by the door knocking sound. a little pause, the door opens, and after a little longer pause, the door slams shut. Cool. But what about the soundtrack? I opened up my folder of mp3s to look for something instrumental. None of my crappy punk music was gonna cut it, but I did find a nice Christmas piece that would do the trick (Sleigh Ride by Manheim Steamroller, in case you care). I added that track to the project and now I had something to work with. Except a movie...</p>

<p>Since I already had the sounds all layed out in somewhat of a decent timing, I decided I would film my movie to the soundtrack. So I built a quick set, fired up MonkeyJam, and had a little movie in no time. I quickly realized however that my poor movie timing combined with my poor audio timing was resulting in two pieces that did not join up nicely at all. Bleah. Well, reshooting the movie seemed like too much work, so I decided to just adjust the soundtrack in Audacity. It couldnt have been easier. I just left my little MonkeyJam preview window open and stepped through the frames. Every time a key frame came up that required synching with a sound, I made note of the frame, divided by 15 (fps) and then put my sound at that point in the mix. Mental note: in the future when making real movies, shoot the movie first, then add in the sound track. (This only underscores how impressive that Thriller video was to sync up all of the animation with an exisiting soundtrack).</p>

<p>Once I had the soundtrack looking good, I exported it as a .WAV file. Then I opened up Axogon Composer and added my video track and my audio track and rendered them together. I ran the output through VirtualDub to compress the whole thing, and presto! - I had my first movie with sound.</p>

<p>Anyway, here is <em>A Christmas Suprise</em> for your viewing pleasure:</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/-GmuR89mcqs?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2005 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/lego_study_3</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_3_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stop-motion Study 2 - New Camera</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/lego_study_2</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_2.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>After seeing Josh's movies and making a few of my own, I am totally hooked on this stop-motion animation stuff. I decided that if I am gonna become a world-renowned lego animator, then I better improve my studio a bit. I bought a new <a href="http://www.logitech.com/index.cfm?page=products/details&amp;CRID=4&amp;amp;CONTENTID=5042&amp;countryid=19&amp;languageid=1">Logitech QuickCam Pro 4000 camera</a> and a couple of cheap desk lamps from target (one with a fancy clip-thingy for a base). The Logitech camera seems to be the camera of choice for a lot of folks on <a href="http://www.brickfilms.com/resources.php">brickfilms.com</a>, and I see why. The quaility of the picture is great, and it has built in zoom and pan functionality. (It has a built-in microphone as well, but that will have to wait for another day).</p>

<p>Anyway, this second study was supposed to be focusing on moving multiple figures at the same time, varying their speed, working on my timing. However, I mostly just ended up playing with my camera. I made two movies during this test, the first is just a collection of random studies that I did (two people, car driving, flower growing, guy rolling on the ground, and a guy levitating); the second doesnt even have any animation, it just tests the zoomming and panning of the camera. Nothing special, but notice that the image quality is getting better. I still need to work on my lighting setup (I still have hotspots and glare and some shadows), but it is an improvement.</p>

<p>Camera test:</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/nJCn7nCAhjY?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

<p>Zoom/pan test:</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/biRo_NJ2_pw?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2005 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/lego_study_2</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_2_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Stop-motion Study 1 - Software Test</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/lego_study_1</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_1.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>For my first venture into stop-motion animation, I figured I would do a few simple software tests to familiarize myself with all of the tools needed to create the final product. Really, I only tested the video capture software (<a href="http://www.giantscreamingrobotmonkeys.com/monkeyjam/">MonkeyJam</a>), the compositing software (Axogon Composer), and the encoding software (<a href="http://www.virtualdub.org/">VirtualDub</a> using the <a href="http://www.xvid.org/">Xvid</a> codec). (Other software dealing with sound effects and audio will have to wait until I get to that point in my testing).</p>

<p>Josh loaned me a couple of webcams to get me up and running, and thanks to a couple of great tutorials on <a href="http://www.brickfilms.com/resources.php">brickfilms.com</a>, I was creating my first movie in no time. This first movie consists of two parts: the first is a simple walking scene to try out the video capture, and the second is an even more simplistic scene that was filmed solely to be the base used to try out features in Axogon.</p>

<p>Here are the results of my first ever attempt at stop-motion animation:</p>

<p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/vHfoRs853a0?rel=0" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>

<p>Pretty unimpressive, to be sure. But even with this simple test, I have learned several things:</p>

<ol>
<li>Webcams are not the greatest cameras in the world. Focusing and getting the colors right and trying not to end up with grainy images will be a challenge.</li>
<li>Lighting is <em>super</em> important. I played around with a couple of (less than optimal) set ups, including using some white paper as backgrounds. It seems like the light needs to be plentiful, but not direct. Legos are suprisingly shiny and reflective.</li>
<li>Patience is a virtue. Ok, so I didnt learn this tonight, but it was proven to me over and over again. In my first clip, I just wanted Mr. Lego to walk about five inches across the screen, but at 24 frames per second, that translates to <em>a lot</em> of frames.</li>
<li>My timing needs work. I originally recorded the walking scene at 15fps, but the poor little lego guy was going so slow, I felt bad for him. By speeding him up to 24fps, he seemed to be moving at a realistic pace (as realistic as an inanimate lego guy trying to walk on his own can be).</li>
<li>Axogon Composer is cool! Lightsaber effects on my first day!?!? That was awesome.</li>
<li>This hobby has the potential to be very addicting. Although you are moving the pieces in such small increments and all that work translates into a few choppy seconds of video, it is suprisingly fun.</li>
</ol>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2005 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/lego_study_1</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/lego_1_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>FJ40 Project</title>
            <link>https://briandunnington.com/fj40</link>
            <description><![CDATA[
<div><img src='https://briandunnington.com/img/fj40_before.jpg' style='max-width:100%;height:auto;' /></div><p>Ever since I was a kid, I dreamed of rebuilding an old FJ40 LandCruiser.</p>

<p>And now I am about to.</p>

<p>Follow along at <a href="http://fj40.blogspot.com">http://fj40.blogspot.com</a></p>

<p><img src="/img/fj40/before/left_front.jpg" class="smallimg" /></p>

]]></description>
            <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2004 12:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <guid>https://briandunnington.com/fj40</guid>
            <image>https://briandunnington.com/img/fj40_before_thumb.jpg</image>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
